<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://ksubbu199.github.io/index.html</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2024-09-07T10:15:15.919Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://ksubbu199.github.io/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://ksubbu199.github.io/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Second Byju’s auditor exits in a year as financial turmoil deepens]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/second-byjus-auditor-exits-in-a-year-as-financial-turmoil-deepens/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/second-byjus-auditor-exits-in-a-year-as-financial-turmoil-deepens/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T18:17:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[BDO, the auditor for Indian edtech startup Byju’s, has resigned with immediate effect, marking the second auditor departure for the embattled startup in about a year and further intensifying concerns about its financial health and governance.
In a scathing resignation letter, BDO subsidiary MSKA highlighted multiple issues with Byju’s, including significant delays in financial reporting, inadequate management support, and concerns over the company’s ability to recover substantial dues from a Dubai-based entity.




The auditor’s exit comes as Byju’s, once India’s most valuable startup with a $22 billion valuation, grapples with a series of crises, including a recent Supreme Court decision to resume insolvency proceedings against the startup.
Deloitte, Byju’s previous auditor, and the start…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google to receive punishment for search monopoly by next August, says judge]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/google-to-receive-punishment-for-search-monopoly-by-next-august-says-judge/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/google-to-receive-punishment-for-search-monopoly-by-next-august-says-judge/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T14:40:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A federal judge says he will deliver a punishment in Google’s antitrust case by August 2025, according to The New York Times, after ruling earlier this month that Google had abused its monopoly power over the search industry.
Judge Amit P. Mehta established a timeline for the remedies phase of Google’s antirust trial during a hearing in Washington, D.C. on Friday, the outcome of which could upend how people find information on the internet. Prosecutors have until the end of the year to submit their proposals, which could take aim at Google’s billion-dollar payments to Apple in exchange for priority placement, or potentially order Google to sell off parts of its business.
A lot can change in one year, however, especially given the upcoming U.S. presidential election. Republican and Democratic donors are both reportedly asking the candidates to shake up America’s tough regulatory environment. The outcome of Google Search’s antitrust case could be on the negotiating table in those discussions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ChatGPT: Everything you need to know about the AI-powered chatbot]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/chatgpt-everything-to-know-about-the-ai-chatbot/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/chatgpt-everything-to-know-about-the-ai-chatbot/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T14:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ChatGPT, OpenAI’s text-generating AI chatbot, has taken the world by storm since its launch in November 2022. What started as a tool to hyper-charge productivity through writing essays and code with short text prompts has evolved into a behemoth used by more than 92% of Fortune 500 companies.
That growth has propelled OpenAI itself into becoming one of the most-hyped companies in recent memory. And its latest partnership with Apple for its upcoming generative AI offering, Apple Intelligence, has given the company another significant bump in the AI race.




2024 also saw the release of GPT-4o, OpenAI’s new flagship omni model for ChatGPT. GPT-4o is now the default free model, complete with voice and vision capabilities. But after demoing GPT-4o, OpenAI paused one of its voices, Sky, after …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The maiden voyage of Blue Origin’s massive new rocket won’t be for NASA]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/the-maiden-voyage-of-blue-origins-massive-new-rocket-wont-be-for-nasa/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/the-maiden-voyage-of-blue-origins-massive-new-rocket-wont-be-for-nasa/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T13:34:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The world will have to wait a little longer to see Blue Origin’s massive New Glenn rocket fly for the first time.
That rocket had been scheduled to launch two spacecraft to Mars for NASA during an eight-day window that opens on October 13. But NASA announced on Friday that it was pushing the mission, called ESCAPADE, to spring 2025, citing potential cost and technical issues with de-fueling the two satellites. New Glenn will now launch some of the company’s own technology in November instead.




The first launch of a new rocket always poses enormous risk, both to the launch vehicle and the payload, and Blue Origin has been racing to get New Glenn ready for launch in a month’s time. Blue Origin CEO Dave Limp acknowledged in a post on X that there was still much to do: “Still lots to do but…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watch live as Boeing and NASA attempt to bring empty Starliner back to Earth]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/watch-live-as-boeing-and-nasa-attempt-to-bring-empty-starliner-back-to-earth/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/watch-live-as-boeing-and-nasa-attempt-to-bring-empty-starliner-back-to-earth/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T13:22:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After 93 days on orbit, Starliner is coming home. 
The spacecraft is a “go” for undocking from the International Space Station at 6:04 p.m. EST, though it will be leaving its two-person crew behind, and you can watch the drama unfold live.




Those crew members, NASA astronauts Butch Wilmore and Suni Williams, closed the hatch on Starliner for the final time earlier today. They’ll be monitoring the spacecraft as it makes its way through the atmosphere this evening, before eventually landing in New Mexico shortly after midnight. 
Boeing’s Starliner spacecraft launched to orbit on June 5. This crewed test mission was the critical final step before the company could start providing regular crew transportation services to the space agency, as part of a $4.2 billion contract it won way back in…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Show HN: Wealthfolio: Private, open-source investment tracker]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41465735</id>
        <link href="https://wealthfolio.app/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T12:56:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thank you for your comments, just some context:
- The app is a simple desktop application that works on macOS, Windows, and Ubuntu.
- I developed this app for my own needs. Getting tired of SaaS app subscriptions and privacy concerns.
- For now, the activities are logged manually or imported from a CSV file. No integration with Plaid or other platforms.
- No monetization is planned for now (only a "buy me a coffee" if you use and appreciate the app).
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41465735
Points: 506
# Comments: 171]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>a-fadil</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wealthy Harris donors are reportedly pressing for ouster of FTC Chair Lina Khan]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/wealthy-harris-donors-are-reportedly-pressing-for-ouster-of-ftc-chair-lina-khan/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/wealthy-harris-donors-are-reportedly-pressing-for-ouster-of-ftc-chair-lina-khan/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T12:52:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some of Vice President Kamala Harris’s wealthier donors are informally asking for FTC Chair Lina Khan to be replaced, reports Bloomberg. It’s not really surprising: her expansive definition of antitrust enforcement has countless industries frantic, and the largest corporations opposed her appointment from the start.
Khan’s FTC, which has opposed mergers that would have been waved through by previous FTC chairs, has seen mixed success. But her nomination by President Biden in 2021 was clearly a challenge to longstanding doctrines that allowed mega-corporations, including “Big Tech,” to consolidate power. She went so far as to call them “mob bosses” in a recent interview with TechCrunch.
The donor pressure may be misplaced, considering that Khan’s term ends later this month. While she will remain in place until the next agency chief is appointed, chances are this will extend her term by months, not years.
Meanwhile, the donors reportedly also expressed a dislike of SEC Chairman Gary Gensler, whose term ends in June 2026.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How a cold email to a VC helped salon software startup Mangomint raise $35M]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/how-a-cold-email-to-a-vc-helped-salon-software-startup-mangomint-raise-35m/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/how-a-cold-email-to-a-vc-helped-salon-software-startup-mangomint-raise-35m/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T12:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in 2017, Daniel Lang, Dan Poineau, and Sandra Huber came together to build Mangomint, a startup that makes salon and spa operations software.
Lang said they realized that software providers were trying to build their own booking platforms, à la OpenTable. “We fundamentally didn’t believe this was the right approach for beauty and wellness,” Lang told TechCrunch. The founders envisioned all-in-one software that booked appointments and then automated ongoing text communications that could do everything from appointment reminders to sending care instructions prior to a skincare procedure.




The company works mainly with small and medium-sized businesses (SMBs) that employ at least five technicians such as estheticians or nail technicians. The software helps automate tasks from client b…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[University of Texas opens robotics program up to incoming freshmen]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/university-of-texas-opens-robotics-program-up-to-incoming-freshmen/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/university-of-texas-opens-robotics-program-up-to-incoming-freshmen/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T11:06:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The University of Texas at Austin this week announced that it has opened its undergraduate robotics program to high school applicants. The honors program is one of the first in the U.S. that allows incoming freshmen to apply for the program as part of their initial admission application. It’s a clear indication that robotics is no longer in the realm of hyper-specialized graduate and doctorate programs.
The minor is tied to a handful of other majors, including aerospace engineering, electrical and computer engineering, computational engineering, computer science and mechanical engineering. Each forms a foundational piece of an eventual robotics major. With the rise of robotics in high school STEAM teaching, the program is designed to maintain incoming freshmen’s interest in the growing space.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[C-Zero is raising $18M to make emission-free hydrogen using natural gas, filings reveal]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/c-zero-is-raising-18m-to-make-emission-free-hydrogen-using-natural-gas-filings-reveal/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/c-zero-is-raising-18m-to-make-emission-free-hydrogen-using-natural-gas-filings-reveal/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T09:57:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hydrogen startup C-Zero has raised $5 million of an $18 million funding round, according to an SEC filing.
The company is developing a way to strip hydrogen from methane without emitting carbon dioxide. The resulting hydrogen can be used in a range of industries today, including ammonia and petrochemical production, and potentially others in the near future, including transportation and steel production. The solid carbon waste product has the potential to be reused in everything from asphalt to lithium-ion batteries.




C-Zero raised a $34 million round valued at $124 million post-money in 2022, according to PitchBook data. The smaller target for the new round suggests the company is being realistic about its prospects following its sizable haul during the pandemic.
The company did not immediately reply to a request for comment.
The process C-Zero employs is known as methane pyrolysis. C-Zero’s reactor heats natural gas in the presence of a proprietary catalyst to break hydrogen’s chemical bond with the central carbon atom in a methane molecule. 
By using readily available natural gas as the feedstock, C-Zero hopes to produce emission-free hydrogen for less than other green hydrogen startups, which typically rely on expensive electrolyzers powered by low-cost renewable energy from wind and solar. 
Tapping into existing natural gas infrastructure also makes methane pyrolysis a natural fit for petrochemical plants, which today use natural gas throughout their operations and also require large amounts of hydrogen to produce various chemicals.
The potential to sell low-cost, zero-emission hydrogen to large, established customers has caused a flurry of startup activity in the space, many of which use methane pyrolysis. A number of competing startups, including Modern Hydrogen, Molten Industries and ReCarbon, also use the process.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meta will let third-party apps place calls to WhatsApp and Messenger users — in 2027]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/meta-will-let-third-party-apps-place-calls-to-whatsapp-and-messenger-users-in-2027/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/meta-will-let-third-party-apps-place-calls-to-whatsapp-and-messenger-users-in-2027/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T09:53:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meta on Friday published an update on how it plans to comply with the Digital Markets Act (DMA), the European law that aims to promote competition in digital marketplaces, where the law concerns the company’s messaging apps, Messenger and WhatsApp.
As Meta notes in a blog post, the DMA requires that it provide an option in WhatsApp and Messenger to connect with interoperable third-party messaging services and apps. Meta says it’s building notifications into WhatsApp and Messenger to inform users about these third-party integrations and alert them when a newly compatible third-party messaging app comes online.


The company also says it’s introducing an onboarding flow in WhatsApp and Messenger where users can learn more about third-party chats and switch them on. From the flow, users will …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Roblox introduces new earning opportunities for creators, teases generative AI project]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/roblox-introduces-new-earning-opportunities-for-creators-teases-generative-ai-project/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/roblox-introduces-new-earning-opportunities-for-creators-teases-generative-ai-project/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the annual Roblox Developers Conference, the company announced on Friday a series of upcoming changes coming to the platform in the next few months and years. Most notably, Roblox is adding more ways for creators to earn money through their experiences, and the company is unveiling a project that will power generative AI creation on the platform. 
The company is introducing a new program that will give creators a higher share of revenue for their paid experiences on the desktop. Creators will now receive 50% of the revenue for paid experiences that cost $9.99, 60% for experiences that cost $29.99 and 70% for experiences that cost $49.99. The change marks a significant increase in revenue sharing, as creators currently earn about 25% of the revenue for their paid experiences. 




Roblox…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Startups have to be clever when fighting larger rivals]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/startups-have-to-be-clever-when-fighting-larger-rivals/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/startups-have-to-be-clever-when-fighting-larger-rivals/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T09:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to Startups Weekly — your weekly recap of everything you can’t miss from the world of startups. Want it in your inbox every Friday? Sign up here.
You won’t find any Founder Mode discourse in this week’s newsletter, although the memes keep coming. Instead, here’s your usual dose of startup news, from oversized rounds, to pivots, to new product launches.
Most interesting startup stories from the week


When facing bigger rivals, startups often have to be clever on how to fight. There’s no right answer, which explains why many change their mind along the way when they don’t get a lucky break.




Brighter sky: X’s shutdown in Brazil is benefiting rival social network Bluesky, which saw a massive influx of newcomers since last weekend. This was particularly noticeable, as it’s still mu…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NFL kicks off in Brazil for the first time, but reporters and fans can’t post on X due to nationwide ban]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/nfl-season-kicks-off-in-brazil-but-reporters-and-fans-cant-post-on-x-due-to-nationwide-ban/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/nfl-season-kicks-off-in-brazil-but-reporters-and-fans-cant-post-on-x-due-to-nationwide-ban/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T08:49:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Philadelphia Eagles and the Green Bay Packers will face off tonight in their first game of the NFL season. But this season opener is a bit different. As the league seeks to expand into international markets, the two football teams have traveled to Brazil to make history by playing the first-ever regular season NFL game in South America.
For sports journalists and dedicated football fans who have traveled to São Paulo, the weekend presents an unexpected obstacle: X is now banned in Brazil.




A lot has changed on the app formerly known as Twitter since Elon Musk bought it in 2022. But what has remained constant is that it is indispensable to sports fans. Unlike Instagram, TikTok or other popular social media apps, the microblogging platform offers the perfect format to dash off quick, …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VC pitch show ‘Meet the Drapers’ partners with TikTok]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/vc-pitch-show-meet-the-drapers-partners-with-tiktok/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/vc-pitch-show-meet-the-drapers-partners-with-tiktok/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T08:44:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Venture capitalist Tim Draper’s international pitch competition, “Meet the Drapers,” is partnering up with TikTok as it heads into its seventh season. Under the new tie-up, entrepreneurs will pitch their startups to the public through the short-form video app for one of the show’s upcoming episodes. The general public will then be able to vote on their favorite submissions through a landing page in the app followed by a livestreamed pitch review on TikTok. This will all culminate in the selection of four finalists, who will compete on an episode of the show in front of judges in hopes of winning the $1 million investment from Tim Draper.
For TikTok, the deal allows the company to position itself as a champion for small businesses at a time when its platform is under an increasingly unpopul…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Public EV startup with an indicted CEO is looking to raise an additional $100 million]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/public-ev-startup-with-an-indicted-ceo-is-looking-to-raise-an-additional-100-million/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/public-ev-startup-with-an-indicted-ceo-is-looking-to-raise-an-additional-100-million/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T08:25:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s tempting to think the trend of EV startups merging with special purpose acquisition companies (SPACs) to go public has ended, seeing how many of them are struggling or defunct. But that’s not quite true. A startup called Thunder Power Holdings went public on the Nasdaq exchange in June through a SPAC, and is now trying to raise up to $100 million more through a share sale deal. 
All this is happening even as the CEO of the company, Wellen Sham, has been indicted by the Taiwanese government on 11 criminal charges. 




It’s all right there in Thunder Power’s filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission, which are required for all public companies. Thunder Power spells it out on page 46 of this amended S-4 filing from April, where it explains that the Taipei District Prosecutor’s…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Indian companies are lagging?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MdHLd9BamX0</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MdHLd9BamX0"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T07:38:16.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Think School</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The New Data Pipeline: Fivetran, DataStax and NEA are coming to TechCrunch Disrupt 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/the-new-data-pipeline-fivetran-datastax-and-nea-are-coming-to-techcrunch-disrupt-2024/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/the-new-data-pipeline-fivetran-datastax-and-nea-are-coming-to-techcrunch-disrupt-2024/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T07:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the world of modern AI, data is more than just a resource — it’s the fundamental core that aligns decision-makers, supports processes and enables innovation. As AI applications become more robust and pervasive, the pace of such advancement is only as good as the evolution of the data infrastructure behind it. 
We are delighted to discuss the data deluge with industry experts George Fraser, CEO of Fivetran; Chet Kapoor, chairman and CEO of DataStax; and Vanessa Larco, partner at NEA, live on the SaaS Stage at TechCrunch Disrupt 2024. 




The panel will dive deep into the shift from mere data accumulation to meaningful integration, exploring how businesses are building, managing, securing and scaling their data infrastructures. They’ll share insights on what’s on the horizon for data evo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Did Sandia use a thermonuclear secondary in a product logo?]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41463809</id>
        <link href="https://blog.nuclearsecrecy.com/2024/09/04/did-sandia-use-a-thermonuclear-secondary-in-a-product-logo/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T07:27:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://blog.nuclearsecrecy.com/2024/09/04/did-sandia-use-a-thermonuclear-secondary-in-a-product-logo/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41463809
Points: 509
# Comments: 168]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>terryf</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2M users but no money in the bank]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41463734</id>
        <link href="https://exercism.org/blog/september-2024-restructure"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T07:16:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://exercism.org/blog/september-2024-restructure
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41463734
Points: 513
# Comments: 286]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>leandot</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transport for London outages drag into weekend after cyberattack]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/transport-for-london-outages-drag-into-weekend-after-cyberattack/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/transport-for-london-outages-drag-into-weekend-after-cyberattack/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T07:05:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Transport for London, the government body overseeing the U.K. capital’s public transit system, said it is experiencing online outages due to an “ongoing cyber security incident” set to drag into the weekend. 
TfL, which runs the London Underground (known as the Tube), buses and trams across London, said that while the city’s public transit system is “operating as usual,” several customer-facing systems are offline, including some ticketing systems and its online real-time Tube arrival information. 




Details of the incident remain scarce. TfL disclosed the cyberattack earlier this week, and said that the government body took action to “prevent further access to its systems.” 
In a brief update on its website on Friday, TfL said it has no evidence yet that any customer data was compromised in the cyberattack. 
A spokesperson for TfL did not respond to a request for comment about what evidence, such as logs, the organization has to determine if any data was stolen. It’s unclear if the organization is able to receive email due to the cyberattack. According to the cyber incident page, TfL says, “many of our staff have limited access to systems and email and, as a result, we may be delayed or unable to respond to your query or any webforms previously submitted.”
According to sources speaking to BBC News, TfL employees have been told to work from home as much of the organization’s back-office systems at its headquarters are affected. 
A review by TechCrunch of TfL’s public-facing web infrastructure shows much of the organization’s systems are no longer online, or have been restricted from accessing the public internet, likely in an effort to isolate the intruders and prevent further access. 




At the time of writing, TechCrunch found several TfL systems, including its employee log-on portal, were still accessible from the internet.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Instagram DMs get upgraded with new features]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/instagram-is-adding-new-photo-editing-features-to-dms/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/instagram-is-adding-new-photo-editing-features-to-dms/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Instagram is jazzing up the inbox by adding new features for photo editing, sticker creation, and themes. The company is trying to make Instagram more appealing as a messaging app with features to make conversations more engaging. While some of these features might not sound new, it’s all about removing friction for users that might prevent them from sending a message.
In addition, the inbox — or DMs (direct messages) are a competitive feature for social apps, including those that are taking on Twitter/X. While other startups like Bluesky are integrating DMs directly into their app, Instagram’s X rival Threads is still relying on Instagram’s existing DMs for those who want to connect privately. 




With today’s release of new features, Instagram users will gain access to a sticker maker i…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Last call: Boost your brand by hosting a Side Event at TechCrunch Disrupt 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/last-call-boost-your-brand-by-hosting-a-side-event-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2024/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/last-call-boost-your-brand-by-hosting-a-side-event-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2024/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Keep the excitement of TechCrunch Disrupt 2024 alive by hosting an exclusive Side Event after hours. Don’t miss out — today is the final day to apply for free!
Maximize your brand’s exposure to 10,000 Disrupt attendees and the dynamic Bay Area tech scene during “Disrupt Week” — taking place October 26 through November 1. Whether it’s a cocktail party, a casual happy hour, a niche meetup, a skill-building workshop, a silent disco, or a comedy night, choose the event that aligns with your brand’s vibe.




Submit your application before tonight’s deadline.
Perks of hosting a Side Event
Maximize your reach! Engage with thousands of Disrupt 2024 attendees and the broader tech community. We’ll spotlight your Side Event across various platforms, ensuring it connects with our wide and diverse audience:
Disrupt 2024 Side Event page
Disrupt 2024 Agenda
Disrupt 2024 Mobile App Agenda
Disrupt 2024 attendee emails
Disrupt 2024 articles
Exclusive discount benefits for you and your network! As a Side Event host, you’ll get a personalized discount code for Disrupt 2024 tickets. Pass it along to your team and your connections so everyone can take advantage of this offer.
Host a Side Event before tonight’s deadline
Seize the opportunity to shine at one of the year’s most anticipated tech events with your very own Side Event. “Disrupt Week” is your chance to be at the heart of the startup world. Start your application now before today ends!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Students and recent grads: Last day to save on TechCrunch Disrupt 2024 Student Passes]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/students-and-recent-grads-last-day-to-save-on-techcrunch-disrupt-2024-student-passes/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/students-and-recent-grads-last-day-to-save-on-techcrunch-disrupt-2024-student-passes/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T06:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today’s your final chance to secure your TechCrunch Disrupt 2024 Student Pass with a $200 discount! Maximize your savings by opting for the Student 4+ Bundle and bring four or more of your friends along for the experience. Prices go up after midnight, so don’t miss your opportunity to save.
Now that the semester is in full swing and the job market remains competitive for recent graduates, we recognize the financial pressure many are under. This discount is here to lend a hand when it’s needed most.




Accelerate your career by networking with over 10,000 tech, startup, and VC leaders at Disrupt 2024, taking place from October 28-30 at Moscone West in San Francisco. It’s the perfect opportunity to boost your chances of landing your first job after college.
Lock in your Student Pass discoun…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Real estate revolutions and beanie baby economies]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/real-estate-revolutions-and-beanie-baby-economies/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/real-estate-revolutions-and-beanie-baby-economies/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T06:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Listen on
Apple Podcasts




Listen on
Spotify





The Equity podcast crew is wrapping up another eventful week, with real estate, AI agents, gambling, and secondary markets — which are, of course, a form of legalized gambling.
Mary Ann Azevedo, Becca Szkutak, and Devin Coldewey started off this Friday’s episode with the acknowledgment that the X/Twitter ban situation in Brazil is possibly too complicated an issue to even have an opinion on. Let us cook on that for a bit.




In the deals of the week, Devin first talked about You.com’s $50 million play to take on more difficult AI tasks, things that can’t be solved with a quick Google search. The company is hoping to be the go-to for complex stuff that mixes live search, coding, and natural language understanding — and unlike a lot of its…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google faces provisional antitrust charges in UK for ‘self-preferencing’ its ad exchange]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/google-faces-provisional-antitrust-charges-in-uk-for-self-preferencing-its-ad-exchange/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/google-faces-provisional-antitrust-charges-in-uk-for-self-preferencing-its-ad-exchange/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T02:41:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More antitrust woes for Google. The U.K’.s competition watchdog said on Friday that it suspects the company of adtech antitrust abuses. The tech giant will now have a chance to respond to the provisional findings before the regulator reaches a final decision.
Confirmed violations of U.K. competition law can lead to corrective orders and fines of up to 10% of annual worldwide group turnover. So the outcome of this case is likely to be closely watched.




The U.K.’s Competition and Markets Authority (CMA) has been investigating Google’s role in the adtech stack over suspected abuses of dominance since May 2022. The new development is the sending of a formal statement of objections to Google setting out provisional findings that accuse the adtech giant of self-preferencing its own ad exchang…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Karo is a to-do app that lets you assign tasks to your friends and family]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/karo-is-a-to-do-app-that-lets-you-assign-tasks-to-your-friends-and-family/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/karo-is-a-to-do-app-that-lets-you-assign-tasks-to-your-friends-and-family/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T02:19:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can build a reminder and task management system for yourself, and use a service that works for your team. But it might not be easy to get your family members or friends to use the same task management app. iOS app Karo (which means “do it” in Hindi) aims to solve the problem even if the other person doesn’t use the app.
This isn’t Mustafa Yusuf‘s first task management product. The India-based developer also develops another to-do app called Tasks, for more complex task management. Yusuf told TechCrunch that he developed Karo because other apps didn’t allow him the flexibility of assigning tasks to people in your address book.




“No app allowed me to simply delegate and track tasks I had for people in my contacts. For example, my accountant, sister, plumber, or electrician. I just wan…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elon Musk’s X could still face sanctions for training Grok on Europeans’ data]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/elon-musks-x-could-still-face-sanctions-for-training-grok-on-europeans-data/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/06/elon-musks-x-could-still-face-sanctions-for-training-grok-on-europeans-data/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T01:33:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this week, the EU’s lead privacy regulator ended its court proceeding related to how X processed user data to train its Grok AI chatbot, but the saga isn’t over yet for the Elon Musk-owned social media platform formerly known as Twitter. The Irish Data Protection Commission (DPC) has confirmed to TechCrunch that it’s received — and will “examine” — a number of complaints that have been filed under the bloc’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). 
“The DPC will now examine the extent to which any processing that has taken place complies with the relevant provisions of the GDPR,” the regulator told TechCrunch. “If, further to that examination, it is established that TUIC [Twitter International Unlimited Company, as X’s main Irish subsidiary is still known] has infringed the GDPR…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell HN: Burnout is bad to your brain, take care]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41461499</id>
        <link href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41461499"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T23:59:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am depressed and burned out for quite some time already, unfortunately my brain still couldn't recover from it.
If I summarize the impact of burnout to my brain:
- Before: I could learn things pretty quickly, come up with solutions to the problems, even be able to see common patterns and see bigger underlying problems
- After: can't learn, can't work, can't remember, can't see solutions for trivial problems (e.g. if your shirt is wet, you can change it, but I stare at it thinking when it is going to get dried up)
Take care of your mental health
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41461499
Points: 503
# Comments: 202]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>tuyguntn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Telegram quietly enables users to report private chats to moderators after founder’s arrest]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/telegram-quietly-enables-users-to-report-private-chats-to-moderators-after-founders-arrest/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/telegram-quietly-enables-users-to-report-private-chats-to-moderators-after-founders-arrest/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T18:32:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Telegram has quietly updated its policy to allow users to report private chats to its moderators following the arrest of founder Pavel Durov in France over “crimes committed by third parties” on the platform. 
The messaging app, which serves nearly 1 billion monthly active users, has long maintained a reputation for minimal supervision of user interactions.




On Thursday night, Telegram began implementing changes to its moderation policy. “All Telegram apps have ‘Report’ buttons that let you flag illegal content for our moderators — in just a few taps,” the company states on its updated frequently-asked-questions page. 
The platform has also provided an email address for automated takedown requests, instructing users to include links to content requiring moderator attention.
It’s unclear how, and whether, this change impacts Telegram’s ability to respond to requests from law enforcement agencies. The company has previously cooperated with court orders to share some information about its users. 
TechCrunch has reached out to Telegram for comment. 
The Dubai-headquartered company has additionally edited its FAQ page, removing two sentences that previously emphasized its privacy stance on private chats. The earlier version had stated: “All Telegram chats and group chats are private amongst their participants. We do not process any requests related to them.”




These policy changes follow Durov’s arrest by French authorities in connection with an investigation into crimes related to child sexual abuse images, drug trafficking, and fraudulent transactions. 




Responding to his arrest, Durov posted on his Telegram channel, criticizing the action: “Using laws from the pre-smartphone era to charge a CEO with crimes committed by third parties on the platform he manages is a misguided approach.” 
He argued that the established practice for countries dissatisfied with an internet service is to initiate legal action against the service itself, rather than its management.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Stop harassing Starlink,’ SpaceX President tells Brazilian judge]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/stop-harassing-starlink-spacex-president-tells-brazilian-judge/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/stop-harassing-starlink-spacex-president-tells-brazilian-judge/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T14:55:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SpaceX President Gwynne Shotwell made a public plea to one of Brazil’s top judicial figures on Thursday, asking him to “please stop harassing Starlink” amid the ongoing battle in the country against Elon Musk’s social media business X. 
Musk has been engaged in a months-long dispute with the Brazilian courts, who have been waging a war against X for hosting accounts that the courts say spread extremism and misinformation. 




After X refused to comply with court orders last month asking it to remove certain accounts, Supreme Court Justice Alexandre de Moraes ordered an immediate, country-wide suspension of the platform. That ban, backed by Brazil’s President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva, was unanimously upheld earlier this week. 
But the feud has been spilling over to Musk’s other businesses…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Governing data products using fitness functions]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/fitness-functions-data-products.html</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/fitness-functions-data-products.html"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T13:37:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Decentralized data management requires automation to scale governance
       effectively. Fitness functions are a powerful automated governance
       technique my colleagues have applied to data products within the context
       of a Data Mesh. Since data products serve as the foundational building
       blocks of a data strategy, ensuring robust governance around them
       significantly increases the chances of success. Kiran
       Prakash explains how to do this, starting with simple tests for
       key architectural characteristics and moving on to leveraging metadata
       and Large Language Models.
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Osom is shutting down on Friday, as it had ‘no customers for a mobile phone’]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/osom-is-shutting-down-on-friday/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/osom-is-shutting-down-on-friday/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T13:08:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Launching a phone company is a remarkably difficult — some even say foolish — thing to do. OSOM Products, which rose out of the smoldering ashes of Essential in 2020, is closing shop. Android Authority was first to report the news, after gaining access to an internal announcement from CEO Jason Keats.
OSOM always had a difficult road, with plans to launch a privacy-focused handset. And much like Essential before it, the company dealt with its own legal struggles — namely a lawsuit against filed by a former employee alleging financial mismanagement.




For its part, the company did manage to release a mobile device, though not the first-party phone it had announced. Rather the company lent its technology to a Web3 focused devices from Solana.
OSOM did manage to bring a product to market under its own name. The OSOM Privacy Cable is effectively a USB cord whose data transfer can be disabled in situations where “juice jackers” might be present.
“The report in Android Authority is correct, OSOM is sadly shutting down. In May of 2024, having no customers for a mobile phone despite concerted efforts, OSOM at the time decided to pivot to a new project,” CEO Jason Keats said in a statement provided to TechCrunch. “OSOM was forced to let go of a number of employees at that time to reduce our burn rate.”
The “new project” would appear to refer to an “AI-powered camera” it planned as a followup to its unreleased smartphone. According to initial reports, Keating had attempted to sell the company off to HP, but was unable to strike a deal. 
“Unfortunately, given the bleak market climate for fundraising for consumer electronics startups, we were unable to raise a new round,” Keats says. “While some maintenance operations to ensure contractual requirements will proceed, OSOM’s general operations will shut down on September 6.”]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Salesforce acquires data management firm Own for $1.9B in cash]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/salesforce-acquires-data-management-firm-own-for-1-9b-in-cash/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/salesforce-acquires-data-management-firm-own-for-1-9b-in-cash/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T12:53:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Salesforce has acquired Own Company, a New Jersey-based provider of data management and protection solutions, for $1.9 billion in cash.
Own is Salesforce’s biggest deal since buying Slack for $27.7 billion in 2021. The company reportedly considered — but ultimately decided against — purchasing data management software firm Informatica earlier this year.




In a press release, Salesforce GM Steve Fisher said the acquisition “underscores [Salesforce’s] commitment to providing secure, end-to-end solutions that protect our customers’ most valuable data.”
“Data security has never been more critical, and Own’s proven expertise and products will enhance our ability to offer robust data protection and management solutions to our customers,” Fisher continued. 
Own, launched in 2015 as OwnBackup (t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US charges five Russian military hackers with targeting Ukraine’s government with destructive malware]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/us-charges-five-russian-military-hackers-with-targeting-ukraines-government-with-destructive-malware/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/us-charges-five-russian-military-hackers-with-targeting-ukraines-government-with-destructive-malware/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T10:56:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Thursday, the U.S. Department of Justice accused five members of Russia’s military intelligence agency of hacking several Ukrainian government agencies, an unnamed U.S. government agency in Maryland, and computers belonging to 26 NATO countries, among other victims. 
The DOJ announced the indictment of the five members of Russia’s Main Intelligence Directorate, also known as GRU, and in particular its hacking Unit 29155. The indictment names Russian GRU colonel and commanding officer of cyber operations, Yuriy Denisov; lieutenants Vladislav Borovkov, Denis Denisenko, Dmitriy Goloshubov and Nikolay Korchagin; and a civilian co-conspirator Amin Sitgal, who was previously indicted for some of the same crimes. 




Prosecutors allege that the six indicted individuals were behind the Whisper…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lyft restructures its micromobility business and Volkswagen brings ChatGPT to US vehicles]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/lyft-restructures-its-micromobility-business-and-volkswagen-brings-chatgpt-to-us-vehicles/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/lyft-restructures-its-micromobility-business-and-volkswagen-brings-chatgpt-to-us-vehicles/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome back to TechCrunch Mobility — your central hub for news and insights on the future of transportation. Sign up here for free — just click TechCrunch Mobility!
Short week, shorter newsletter. For all the U.S.-based readers, I hope you had an enjoyable Labor Day. 




Before we jump into the news fray, here is one nifty item that combines robotics, mobility, and accessibility. Korea’s Institute of Machinery and Materials showcased a robotic wheelchair with large, deformable wheels that can manage rocks, stairs and other obstacles. Check it out. 
Now, on to other news. Let’s go!
A little bird


Got a tip for us? Email Kirsten Korosec at kirsten.korosec@techcrunch.com, Sean O’Kane at sean.okane@techcrunch.com or Rebecca Bellan at rebecca.bellan@techcrunch.com. Or check out these instruc…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft gives deepfake porn victims a tool to scrub images from Bing search]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/microsoft-gives-deepfake-porn-victims-a-tool-to-scrub-images-from-bing-search/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/microsoft-gives-deepfake-porn-victims-a-tool-to-scrub-images-from-bing-search/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T10:04:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The advancement of generative AI tools has created a new problem for the internet: the proliferation of synthetic nude images resembling real people. On Thursday, Microsoft took a major step to give revenge porn victims a tool to stop its Bing search engine from returning these images.
Microsoft announced a partnership with StopNCII, an organization that allows victims of revenge porn to create a digital fingerprint of these explicit images, real or not, on their device. StopNCII’s partners then use that digital fingerprint, or “hash” as it’s technically known, to scrub the image from their platforms. Microsoft’s Bing joins Facebook, Instagram, Threads, TikTok, Snapchat, Reddit, PornHub, and OnlyFans in partnering with StopNCII, and using its digital fingerprints to stop the spread of reve…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Driverless car-sharing startup Vay steers toward B2B services]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/driverless-car-sharing-startup-vay-steers-towards-b2b-services/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/driverless-car-sharing-startup-vay-steers-towards-b2b-services/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T09:49:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vay, a startup that has put a teleoperated twist to car-sharing in Berlin and Las Vegas, is expanding into commercial and business-to-business services buoyed by recent deals with French automaker Peugeot and Belgium-based Poppy.
Vay isn’t traditional a ride-hailing or car sharing startup, nor does it operate a robotaxi service. And yet, when customers in Las Vegas or Berlin open the Vay app and hail a car, it arrives without a human behind the wheel.




The Berlin-based startup, which was founded in 2019 and has raised about $110 million to date, has developed teleoperations technology that allows employees sitting in an office to pilot empty vehicles to customers. Once the Vay vehicle arrives, the customer hops in and takes over manual control of the car. Customers drive themselves to t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drip Capital, a fintech that provides working capital to SMBs, picks up $113M]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/drip-capital-a-fintech-that-provides-working-capital-to-smbs-picks-up-113m/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/drip-capital-a-fintech-that-provides-working-capital-to-smbs-picks-up-113m/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T09:27:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For over two decades, Jay Chandarana relied on commercial banks to meet the day-to-day, working capital needs of his family business, the sesame seed exporter Dhaval Agri. It was an arrangement that basically worked: the company grew to have a 13% share of the country’s total exports, making it the largest sesame seed exporter in the market. Yet despite sending seeds to customers in 40 countries, it’s still firmly a medium-sized enterprise, with last year’s revenues clearing just $83 million. 
And it was facing a problem: when Chandarana thought about how he might expand the operation, his bank-based financial arrangement came up short. 




“Banking in India is collateral-based,” Chandarana explained. “Your volumes may grow according to the business you’re doing, but the bank payments wil…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s AI-powered Ask Photos feature begins U.S. rollout]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/googles-ai-powered-ask-photos-feature-begins-u-s-rollout/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/googles-ai-powered-ask-photos-feature-begins-u-s-rollout/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T08:50:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[First announced at Google’s I/O developer conference this May, Google Photos’ AI-powered search feature, “Ask Photos,” is rolling out to users starting Thursday. The feature, which allows users to ask the AI to find photos using more complex queries, will initially be available in “early access” to select customers in the U.S. before expanding to a wider user base.
Powered by Google’s Gemini AI model, Ask Photos lets users search their photos using natural language queries that leverage the AI’s understanding of their photo’s content and other metadata. Previously, Google Photos users could search for particular people, places or things in their photos, but the AI upgrade will allow them to ask a larger variety of questions, including those that require a deeper understanding of the photos…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Endolith is using ‘Olympic caliber’ copper microbes to address the copper shortage]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/endolith-is-using-olympic-caliber-copper-microbes-to-address-the-copper-shortage/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/endolith-is-using-olympic-caliber-copper-microbes-to-address-the-copper-shortage/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T08:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Copper is critical to the energy transition away from fossil fuels. The metal is an excellent conductor of electricity, used in everything from electric vehicles to wind turbines. But by the end of the decade, the International Energy Agency expects copper supplies to fall 20% short of demand.
One stealthily operating startup thinks it can narrow the gap by helping miners extract more copper from their mines. To do that, Colorado-based Endolith is turning to microbes.




Today, most copper is recovered using hydrometallurgy, which generally involves pouring acid on piles of rock, which strips out some portion of the copper. Endolith supplements that, adding what are essentially domesticated microbes that can boost the amount of copper that leaches out of the pile.
“Conservatively, we thin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All Hands AI raises $5M to build open source agents for developers]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/all-hands-ai-raises-5m-to-build-open-source-agents-for-developers/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/all-hands-ai-raises-5m-to-build-open-source-agents-for-developers/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T08:14:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At its best, programming is a creative endeavor, but in this age of shifting everything left, much of a developer’s day is filled with what All Hands AI co-founder and CEO Robert Brennan calls the “toil-oriented task” like writing unit tests, managing dependencies and keeping documentation up to date. AI, on the other hand, may not be creative, but it is pretty good at exactly those routine tasks. 
All Hands AI, which announced a $5 million seed funding round led by Menlo Ventures on Thursday, aims to build model-agnostic open source AI agents that can handle most of this toil and allow developers to focus more of their time on doing what they do best.


A few months ago, AI Cognition showed off Devin, an AI agent that could plan and execute complex engineering tasks — and maybe more impor…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mintlify is building a next-gen platform for writing software docs]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/mintlify-is-building-a-next-gen-platform-for-writing-software-docs/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/mintlify-is-building-a-next-gen-platform-for-writing-software-docs/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T07:58:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Software documentation — the resources that explain how software works and how to use it — has evolved dramatically over the past few decades. Once mostly in the form of PDFs and static plaintext, docs today are more interactive and user-friendly than they used to be.
But crafting them is still a time sink. Han Wang and Hahnbee Lee, both devs and entrepreneurs, say that they’ve personally struggled with this.




“In the 2010s, companies like Stripe, Hashicorp, Twilio and a bunch others raised the bar on developer content,” Wang said. “They proved that a truly great developer experience for their content is not just a commodity, but a competitive advantage. Since then, every company has been trying to catch up, but it’s actually quite difficult.”
Inspired to try simplifying the workflows t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[German LLM maker Aleph Alpha pivots to AI support]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/german-llm-maker-aleph-alpha-pivots-to-ai-support/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/german-llm-maker-aleph-alpha-pivots-to-ai-support/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T07:47:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Europe doesn’t have many large language model (LLM) makers but one of these rare AI beasts — Germany’s Aleph Alpha — appears to be preparing to rule itself out of the running, per Bloomberg, which has an interview with CEO Jonas Andrulis on its pivot to a broader generative AI-support play. 
The idea with a product it unveiled last week, called PhariaAI, is to help other companies or the public sector use AI tools regardless of whether it made the underlying tech. “The world changed,” Andrulis told Bloomberg. “Just having an European LLM is not sufficient as a business model. It doesn’t justify the investment.”
Aleph Alpha raised a $500 million Series B round last November. But with category giants like OpenAI having far beefier war chests to fuel development — and, closer to home, France’s Mistral has also raked in more investor cash — the German startup had its work cut out to stay in the LLM fight.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The AI industry is obsessed with Chatbot Arena, but it might not be the best benchmark]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/the-ai-industry-is-obsessed-with-chatbot-arena-but-it-might-not-be-the-best-benchmark/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/the-ai-industry-is-obsessed-with-chatbot-arena-but-it-might-not-be-the-best-benchmark/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T07:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the past few months, tech execs like Elon Musk have touted the performance of their company’s AI models on a particular benchmark: Chatbot Arena.
Maintained by a non-profit known as LMSYS, Chatbot Arena has become something of an industry obsession. Posts about updates to its model leaderboards garner hundreds of views and reshares across Reddit and X, and the official LMSYS X account has over 54,000 followers. Millions of people have visited the organization’s website in the last year alone.




Still, there are some lingering questions about Chatbot Arena’s ability to tell us how “good” these models really are.
In search of a new benchmark
Before we dive in, let’s take a moment to understand what LMSYS is exactly, and how it became so popular.
The non-profit only launched last April…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rivian’s chief software designer is coming to TechCrunch Disrupt 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/rivians-chief-software-designer-is-coming-to-techcrunch-disrupt-2024/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/rivians-chief-software-designer-is-coming-to-techcrunch-disrupt-2024/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T07:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every automaker is aiming to build and sell the so-called software-defined vehicle. Rivian may have actually done it, but getting there wasn’t easy. Just ask Rivian’s chief of software Wassym Bensaid.
In a bid to drive down manufacturing costs and improve the performance of its EVs, Rivian changed 600 parts on its flagship R1S SUV and R1T pickup truck. The company left the exterior mostly untouched and instead reworked the guts, including the electrical architecture and a redesigned software user interface that provides detailed illustration-like graphics using Unreal Engine as well as deeper integration with Apple and Google.




Bensaid, who joined the EV maker in 2019, drove the creation of the vertically integrated software stack at Rivian. In other words, Bensaid knows a thing or two …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google expands AI-powered virtual try-on tool to include dresses]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/google-expands-ai-powered-virtual-try-on-tool-include-dresses/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/google-expands-ai-powered-virtual-try-on-tool-include-dresses/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T07:10:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google announced Thursday that it expanded its generative AI-powered virtual try-on tool to support dresses, allowing users to virtually wear thousands of dresses from hundreds of brands, including Boden, Maje, Sandro, Simkhai and Staud.
According to the company, dresses were one of the most searched apparel categories for the tool. However, as Google explained in today’s blog post, its current diffusion technique is challenging to use with dresses, as they are more detailed and complex compared to other clothing items. 




To provide more context, Google Shopping released the tool last year, using its own diffusion technology to create high-quality, lifelike images of tops and blouses. It simulates how the clothing would drape, fold, cling, and form wrinkles and shadows on real people in…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zamp targets growing demand for sales tax solutions]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/zamp-targets-growing-demand-for-sales-tax-solutions/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/zamp-targets-growing-demand-for-sales-tax-solutions/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Until six years ago, many e-commerce and SaaS businesses could have avoided paying sales tax to states where they had customers, but no physical presence. But as online shopping grew, states realized they were losing out on tax revenue.
The era of free-riding for online retailers ended in 2018 when South Dakota took Wayfair to court over sales tax collection. The Supreme Court ultimately sided with South Dakota. 




Now, online stores and SaaS companies have to collect sales tax from their customers wherever it’s required, which is not an easy task given that tax laws vary significantly by city, county and state.
Rohit Bhadange, who worked in venture capital and private equity, identified sales tax compliance as a major pain point for e-commerce and SaaS businesses. So, about 18 months ag…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[YouTube to limit teens’ exposure to videos about fitness and weight across global markets]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/youtube-to-limit-teens-exposure-to-videos-about-fitness-and-weight-across-global-markets/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/youtube-to-limit-teens-exposure-to-videos-about-fitness-and-weight-across-global-markets/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T06:06:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[YouTube is going limit teens’ exposure to videos that promote and idealize a certain fitness level or physical appearance, the company announced on Thursday. The safeguard first rolled out in the U.S. last year and is now being introduced to teens globally.
The announcement comes as YouTube has faced criticism over the past few years for potentially harming teens and exposing them to content that could encourage eating disorders. 




The type of content that YouTube will limit exposure to includes videos that compare physical features and idealize certain fitness levels, body types and weight. Separately, YouTube will also limit exposure to videos that display “social aggression” in the form of non-contact fights and intimidation. 
The Google-owned platform notes that this type of content…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[YouTube is developing AI detection tools for music and faces, plus creator controls for AI training]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/youtube-is-developing-ai-detection-tools-for-music-and-faces-plus-creator-controls-for-ai-training/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/youtube-is-developing-ai-detection-tools-for-music-and-faces-plus-creator-controls-for-ai-training/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T05:50:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[YouTube on Thursday announced a new set of AI detection tools to protect creators, including artists, actors, musicians and athletes from having their likeness, including their face and voice, copied and used in other videos. One key component of the new detection technology involved the expansion of YouTube’s existing Content ID system, which today identifies copyright-protected material. This system will be expanded to include new synthetic-singing identification technology to identify AI content that simulates someone’s singing voice. Other detection technologies will be developed to identify when someone’s face is simulated with AI, the company says. 
Also of note, YouTube is in the early stages of coming up with a solution to address the use of its content to train AI models. This has…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US, UK and EU sign on to the Council of Europe’s high-level AI safety treaty]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/us-uk-and-eu-sign-on-to-the-council-of-europes-high-level-ai-safety-treaty/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/us-uk-and-eu-sign-on-to-the-council-of-europes-high-level-ai-safety-treaty/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T05:47:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re not very close to any specifics on how, exactly, AI regulations will be implemented and ensured, but today a swathe of countries including the U.S., the U.K. and the European Union signed up to a treaty on AI safety laid out by the Council of Europe (COE), an international standards and human rights organization.
The Council of Europe Framework Convention on Artificial Intelligence and Human Rights, Democracy, and the Rule of Law — as the treaty is formally called — is described by the COE as “the first-ever international legally binding treaty aimed at ensuring that the use of AI systems is fully consistent with human rights, democracy and the rule of law.” 




At a meeting today in Vilnius, Lithuania, the treaty was formally opened for signature. Alongside the aforementioned trio …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[French cleantech startup Calyxia nets $35M to tackle microplastics pollution]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/french-cleantech-startup-calyxia-nets-35m-to-tackle-microplastics-pollution/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/french-cleantech-startup-calyxia-nets-35m-to-tackle-microplastics-pollution/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T05:34:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[French cleantech startup Calyxia has profitability within sight. The company just raised a $35 million Series B round that will help it further ramp up industrial production of its sustainable alternatives to microparticles and microcapsules, setting it on the path to profitability by 2026. But co-founder and CEO Jamie Walters says the B Corp is just getting started.
The ‘starter’ problem Calyxia is tackling is staggering at global scale: Microplastics are polluting everything around the world, from soils, rivers and beaches to the icy waters of the Arctic — they’re even getting inside our own bodies and brains.




Beyond that, the traditional production methods employed by the materials and chemical industries can cause a range of environmental issues. It’s imperative to green up industr…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ZipRecruiter’s new tool will quickly match and schedule an intro call with potential candidates]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/ziprecruiters-new-tool-will-quickly-match-and-schedule-an-intro-call-with-potential-candidates/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/ziprecruiters-new-tool-will-quickly-match-and-schedule-an-intro-call-with-potential-candidates/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T05:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hiring platform ZipRecruiter is launching a new tool, called ZipIntro, to let employers schedule introductory calls with potential candidates at a set time. The tool will also help recruiters suggest potential candidates using AI.
Employers can input information about the role and select a date and time for introductory calls. After that, ZipIntro matches them with potential candidates using AI and sends them an invitation for the call. The tool takes into account employment, education, skills, certifications, interests, and types of jobs users are looking for while matching. 
Image Credits: ZipRecruiter

Employers can review these responses from candidates, further screen candidates, and line up back-to-back calls. ZipRecruiter then allows employers to connect with candidates through one-on-one video calls on the platform.




The company said these intro sessions are typically 30-minute to 1-hour long, with each intro call lasting about five minutes. It noted that while these are initial screening calls, some organizations also use this tool to hire high-volume roles that may require fewer interview stages.
Image Credits: ZipRecruiter

ZipRecruiter noted that with ZipIntro, employers get their first RSVP from candidates within 20 minutes of posting the job requirement. 
“With ZipIntro, recruiters and hiring managers can forge those critical connections faster to assess the true potential of each candidate,” Megan Allen, SVP of product at ZipRecruiter said in a statement. “For job seekers, we’re excited to provide them with the opportunity to speak with an employer faster, allowing them to showcase their true personality, soft skills, and passion.”
The company is not the only platform utilizing AI to make the hiring process easier. Indeed is also using AI to help people write about their job experiences. Microsoft-owned LinkedIn has deployed an AI tool to help recruiters write better job descriptions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DJI takes another crack at palm-sized drones, and this one is $199]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/dji-takes-another-crack-at-palm-sized-drones/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/dji-takes-another-crack-at-palm-sized-drones/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2017, DJI introduced the Spark. With a palm-sized body, gesture control and a sub-$500 price point, the system was firmly targeted at social media. It was, in essence, a selfie-drone.
The little quadcopter built up a fanbase, though apparently not one large enough to justify its own continued existence. DJI quietly discontinued the device in 2019, replacing it with the Mavic Mini, the smallest member of its wildly popular folding consumer drone line.




This week at IFA in Berlin, DJI is once again going small with the new Neo. Like the Spark before it, the drone’s ability to land in the palm of the user’s hand is a major selling point. Among other things, that’s shorthand for Neo’s small footprint: At 135 grams (0.3 pound), DJI says its the “most compact and lightest” drone it has pro…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Portex founder Brittany Ennix learned the importance of supply chains from Uber and Flexport]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/portex-raises-6-25-million-seed-to-make-freight-shipping-easier/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/portex-raises-6-25-million-seed-to-make-freight-shipping-easier/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brittany Ennix first became interested in supply chains as a child. 
Her grandfather worked for the Ford glass manufacturing plant, where she says he gave her an appreciation for the complexity of building something. When Ennix moved to Silicon Valley and worked for Uber and later Flexport, her fascination for the industry grew, until she had an idea for how make the supply chains more efficient for small and mid-sized businesses. 




“Most of us don’t think about supply chains on a day-to-day basis, but they truly shape everything from what we can buy, where we can buy it, where we live, at what price, which is obviously very top of mind in this economy,” Ennix told TechCrunch. 
Nearly three years ago, she started working on Portex, a company that allows small-to-mid-sized businesses (SM…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Verizon bets on fiber’s staying power as it acquires Frontier for $20B]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/verizon-bets-on-fibers-staying-power-as-it-acquires-frontier-for-20b/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/verizon-bets-on-fibers-staying-power-as-it-acquires-frontier-for-20b/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T03:19:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some major consolidation is afoot in the world of internet communications — and it will have implications for competition and consumer internet access in U.S. On Thursday, Verizon announced that it would gobble up Frontier Communications for $20 billion — more than double Frontier’s market cap at the close of trading the night before.
Frontier offers internet, phone and TV services — it has also partnered with companies like Google and Amazon over the years to bundle other digital services or find new distribution channels. But Verizon’s big interest in the company is its fiber business and the fact that it extends to places that Verizon does not currently cover as well.




Originally based in Tampa, Frontier currently has 2.2 million customers across 25 states, including the lucrative ma…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sedric monitors the communications of employees at financial institutions to ensure compliance]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/sedric-monitors-the-communications-of-employees-at-financial-institutions-to-ensure-compliance/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/sedric-monitors-the-communications-of-employees-at-financial-institutions-to-ensure-compliance/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T03:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For financial institutions, complying with regulations is becoming a costlier proposition. According to a recent poll, 76% of financial services firms increased their compliance expenditure from 2022 to 2023, with most blaming new laws.
With the cost of compliance averaging out to around $10,000 per employee these days, many firms are searching for ways to reduce spending without running afoul of regulators. Entrepreneurs Nir Laznik and Eyal Peleg say that they’ve created a solution — powered by generative AI, as is the trend.




Laznik and Peleg co-founded Sedric, an AI-powered platform designed to help financial institutions implement compliance rules and flag possible issues. Prior to Sedric, Laznik spearheaded several startups, including a photo kiosk software firm, while Peleg spent …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kinsome aims to bridge the generation gap with its new app for kids and grandparents]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/kinsome-new-communication-app-for-kids-and-grandparents/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/05/kinsome-new-communication-app-for-kids-and-grandparents/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T02:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over a year ago, former Session M exec Eben Pingree received the news that his mother was diagnosed with Alzheimer’s. Two days later, his father-in-law was given the same diagnosis. 
To create lasting memories and help his three young children bond with their grandparents, Pingree — along with his co-founders Mike Gerbush, Ashley Hawking, and Brianne Baker — developed Kinsome, a communication platform designed for kids and grandparents to share daily updates and preserve cherished memories.




The app has been in public beta since last year and officially launched to the public on Thursday, just ahead of Grandparents Day.
Alongside the launch announcement, the company revealed to TechCrunch that it secured $1.2 million in pre-seed funding. It’s backed by an impressive roster of investors,…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reonic raises €13 million to help small installers of green tech like heat pumps and solar panels]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/reonic-raises-e13-million-to-help-small-installers-of-green-tech-like-heat-pumps-and-solar-panels/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/reonic-raises-e13-million-to-help-small-installers-of-green-tech-like-heat-pumps-and-solar-panels/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[European regulators are pushing hard for greener energy. The REPowerEU plan calls for 10 million additional heat pumps to be added by 2027, and solar panels are also on the rise. 
But most installations are done by small businesses that could be more productive with better work processes.




This is where German startup Reonic comes in. “We give renewable installers the tools to be extremely efficient, and we do that mainly by providing them with planning and workflow software,” said co-founder Tristan Menzinger (sitting on the right in the picture above).
Menzinger, Lars-Manuel Schneider (sitting in the middle in the picture above), and their university mate and third co-founder Udo Sill all worked at a research institute exploring renewable energy deployment. It sparked their interest i…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS @property and the new style]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41448740</id>
        <link href="https://ryanmulligan.dev/blog/css-property-new-style/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T18:13:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://ryanmulligan.dev/blog/css-property-new-style/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41448740
Points: 501
# Comments: 160]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>surprisetalk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boom’s macOS camera app lets you customize your video call appearance]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/boom-is-a-macos-camera-app-for-customizing-your-video-call-layout/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/boom-is-a-macos-camera-app-for-customizing-your-video-call-layout/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As someone who talks to many people outside my time zone, I often spend at least a few minutes on a video call explaining my location, time, and weather. That information became easier to convey with a Mac app called Boom, now available as a freemium product. 
Boom is a bootstrapped company built by former Shopify employees Robleh Jama and Krishna Satya. The app works with all major video conferencing apps, including Zoom, Google Meet, and Microsoft Teams. Once installed, you can add customized themes to your video call appearances, including your name, designation, location, time, and weather.




Plus, it lets you react through on-screen effects, stickers, and GIFs during calls. You can tweak your appearance, too, with controls for things like brightness, contrast, saturation, shadow, hu…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamicland 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41448022</id>
        <link href="https://dynamicland.org/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T17:02:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://dynamicland.org/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41448022
Points: 505
# Comments: 156]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pulcinella</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Internet Archive has lost its appeal in Hachette vs. Internet Archive]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41447758</id>
        <link href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.ca2.60988/gov.uscourts.ca2.60988.306.1.pdf"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T16:41:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.ca2.60988/gov.uscourts.ca2.60988.306.1.pdf
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41447758
Points: 512
# Comments: 482]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Signez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Those ‘Founder mode’ memes keep coming]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/those-founder-mode-memes-keep-coming/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/those-founder-mode-memes-keep-coming/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T15:14:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you spend time on X or Threads, where snarky memes rise and fall, you’ve probably seen posts referencing “founder mode” over the last few days, like this:
https://www.threads.net/@carnage4life/post/C_eaQAxyIcV




Or maybe this:


kanye actually invented founder mode pic.twitter.com/zKmHM9jk8P
— Jared Palmer (@jaredpalmer) September 3, 2024


You may even have seen this parody about “goblin mode.”
The chatter ties to a recent blog post that Y Combinator founder and dispenser of startup wisdom Paul Graham wrote about how founders like Airbnb’s Brian Chesky often ignore conventional wisdom regarding running a company at scale. That conventional wisdom — hire great people and let them do their thing — actually often turns into “hire professional fakers and let them drive the company into the ground,” Graham says.
Of course, he can’t say exactly what founder mode looks like because every founder does it differently, but he hopes that it will someday be as widely taught as manager mode. In the meantime, the hot takes on his hot take continue.


it’s called “founder mode” it’s about how to run your company as a founder and how that often goes against traditional management practices. it’s basically what i already do but paul graham created a cool name for it in his latest essay. you know who paul graham is? y combinator? pic.twitter.com/rMKo9iGk6P
— sophie (@netcapgirl) September 2, 2024



As a Founder, I'm too busy to find out what Founder Mode is https://t.co/gIlvdNvUuN
— Pascal-Emmanuel Gobry (@pegobry_en) September 4, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz shutters its Miami office after two years]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/andreessen-horowitz-shutters-its-miami-office-after-two-years/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/andreessen-horowitz-shutters-its-miami-office-after-two-years/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T14:48:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz (a16z) has closed a satellite office in Miami Beach just two years into a five-year lease it signed for an 8,300-square-foot space. The reason? Disuse, reports Bloomberg. 
Miami — once a hotspot for crypto, an area of interest for a16z — has struggled to retain venture cash and entrepreneurial talent in recent years, Bloomberg notes, with venture investments dwindling to $400 million in Q2 2024 from $5.5 billion in all of 2022, per Pitchbook.
For a16z, the closure deals a blow to plans it outlined in 2022 to ditch a central HQ for “global outposts” in cities including NYC and Santa Monica. Pitched as an antidote to the remote working arrangements that became commonplace during the pandemic (which a16z co-founders Ben Horowitz and Marc Andreessen once derided as “not a good life“), the outposts were meant to “build relationships” amid founders and help “develop [a16z’s]” culture.
Evidently, things didn’t go quite as planned in Miami.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boeing and NASA prepare to bring Starliner home without its crew on Friday]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/boeing-and-nasa-prepare-to-bring-starliner-home-without-its-crew-on-friday/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/boeing-and-nasa-prepare-to-bring-starliner-home-without-its-crew-on-friday/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T14:37:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NASA officials expressed confidence that Starliner will have a safe and successful return to Earth late Friday evening, though they had enough reservations about the spacecraft’s performance to conclude that the trip should be undertaken without humans on board. 
The high-stakes mission is now set to officially conclude on Friday, with Starliner making its undocking attempt around 6:04 p.m. EST. Should all go to plan, the spacecraft will land at New Mexico’s White Sands Space Harbor approximately six hours later. 




These final maneuvers will bring to a close a troubled first crewed mission for the Boeing-made Starliner. It was meant to be the final certification mission before the vehicle could enter operation as a regular transporter for astronauts traveling to and from the Internation…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook says, ‘How do you do, fellow kids?’]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/facebook-says-how-do-you-do-fellow-kids/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/facebook-says-how-do-you-do-fellow-kids/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T14:07:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in my day, Facebook was cool. Gaggles of middle schoolers trolled the local mall, where we would stop into the Apple Store, find an early MacBook Pro, and take dozens of pictures with gaudy Photo Booth filters to post on Facebook. Sometimes, other teens would forget to log out of their accounts, and we would post something like “i just pooped” before signing into our own accounts.
This isn’t the case anymore. In 2014, the Pew Research Center estimated that 71% of U.S. teens used Facebook; as of 2022, that percentage dropped to 32%, then slightly increased to 33% last year. Other studies from Edison Research have shown the same trend. Though Meta is reticent to share much demographic information about its user base, the app’s head, Tom Alison, said that there are 40 million daily activ…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[E-bike maker Cowboy raises a small funding round as it targets profitability next year]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/e-bike-maker-cowboy-raises-one-last-small-funding-round-before-reaching-profitability/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/e-bike-maker-cowboy-raises-one-last-small-funding-round-before-reaching-profitability/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cowboy, the Brussels-based company that has been designing and selling electric bikes that you can see in major cities across Europe, has closed a small, strategic funding round of €5 million (around $5.5 million at current exchange rates). That includes €1 million in debt facilities.
While the amount isn’t as impressive as some of Cowboy’s previous fundraises, the company has been looking for an investor outside of the traditional European VC firms that have already invested in the startup — an investor that could potentially open new doors. As a result, Cypress Capital is leading the round. The Hong Kong-based investment firm has strong ties with Taiwan, which is a key hub for the global bicycle industry.




“A lot of our Asian-based suppliers are Taiwanese for historical reasons. We ar…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paylocity is acquiring corporate spend startup Airbase for $325M]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/paylocity-acquiring-corporate-spend-startup-airbase-for-325m/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/paylocity-acquiring-corporate-spend-startup-airbase-for-325m/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T13:24:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[HR and payroll software company Paylocity has agreed to acquire corporate spend startup Airbase for $325 million, the companies announced Wednesday.
The deal is subject to regulatory approval and is expected to close in the first or second quarter of Paylocity’s fiscal year, which would be sometime in the next 30 to 60 days. It is being funded by borrowings under Paylocity’s revolving credit facility.




It’s a decent exit for seven-year-old Airbase, which was founded by Thejo Kote in 2017 to provide software to midsized companies seeking to better manage their spending. Its platform included bill payments, corporate cards, and employee reimbursements, among other things.
The San Francisco-based fintech company had raised just over $100 million in equity funding since inception from inves…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ilya Sutskever's SSI Inc raises $1B]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41445413</id>
        <link href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/artificial-intelligence/openai-co-founder-sutskevers-new-safety-focused-ai-startup-ssi-raises-1-billion-2024-09-04/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T13:17:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.reuters.com/technology/artificial-intelligence/openai-co-founder-sutskevers-new-safety-focused-ai-startup-ssi-raises-1-billion-2024-09-04/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41445413
Points: 491
# Comments: 588]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>colesantiago</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Publishers prevail in lawsuit over Internet Archive’s ’emergency’ e-book lending]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/publishers-prevail-in-lawsuit-over-internet-archives-unauthorized-ebook-lending/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/publishers-prevail-in-lawsuit-over-internet-archives-unauthorized-ebook-lending/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T13:02:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A long-running lawsuit over the Internet Archive’s “emergency” e-book lending practices during the COVID-19 pandemic has ended in a loss for the website and a victory for publishers.
The lawsuit concerned the Internet Archive’s National Emergency Library, a program it established at the beginning of the pandemic to allow wider access to some 1.3 million e-books. Previously only able to be checked out one at a time, books were later able to be “borrowed” by many people at once.




The publishers, which already had an uneasy relationship with both the Internet Archive and the digital book-lending community in general, sued soon after in June 2020. The publishers contended that going from single-user borrowing to limitless borrowing essentially turned the system from a notional library into …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ryan Breslow’s $450M Bolt deal said to involve a restraining order now]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/ryan-breslows-lofty-450m-bolt-deal-is-in-trouble/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/ryan-breslows-lofty-450m-bolt-deal-is-in-trouble/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T12:35:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ryan Breslow’s plan to get himself reinstalled as CEO of fintech company Bolt — and push through a $450 million fundraising deal that would value the startup at a staggering $14 billion — has apparently stalled.
According to Forbes, Breslow sent an email to shareholders thanking them for signing off on the deal. The problem is that many of those investors, including Montauk Ventures and Ash Pournouri, claim they didn’t sign off on anything. Montauk’s founder, Philip Krim, told Forbes he does not support the financing, and Breslow didn’t have his permission to be included in a list of investors that had approved the deal.
Meanwhile, BlackRock, along with Hedosophia and Untitled Ventures, reportedly applied for a restraining order in an attempt to “halt” Bolt’s Series F round. The trio claimed through an attorney that Bolt was “coercing its investors by forcing them to choose between paying millions of dollars for new stock or losing most of their existing investment.”
Bolt declined TechCrunch’s request for comment.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Short series app My Drama takes on Character.AI with its new AI companions]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/short-series-app-my-drama-launching-ai-companions/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/short-series-app-my-drama-launching-ai-companions/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T12:23:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maybe a lack of AI characters is what Quibi got wrong. At least, that’s what one startup appears to believe. 
My Drama is a new short series app with more than 30 shows, with a majority of them following a soap opera format in order to hook viewers. The app is now launching an AI-powered chatbot for viewers to get to know the characters in depth, bringing it in closer competition with companies like Character.AI, the a16z-backed chatbot startup.




The short drama app was developed by Holywater, a Ukraine-based media tech startup founded by Bogdan Nesvit (CEO) and Anatolii Kasianov (CTO). The parent company also operates a reading app called My Passion, mainly known for its romance titles. 
Since its launch in April, My Drama has rapidly gained traction, boasting 1 million users and $3 mi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ReMarkable Paper Pro]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41444700</id>
        <link href="https://remarkable.com/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T12:07:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://remarkable.com/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41444700
Points: 527
# Comments: 452]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>buro9</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Woman who allegedly killed two people using Ford BlueCruise charged with DUI homicide]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/woman-who-allegedly-killed-two-people-using-ford-bluecruise-charged-with-dui-homicide/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/woman-who-allegedly-killed-two-people-using-ford-bluecruise-charged-with-dui-homicide/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T11:38:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A 23-year-old woman who allegedly killed two men in March while using Ford’s hands-free system, BlueCruise, has been charged with DUI homicide by Pennsylvania State Police. The woman, Dimple Patel, turned herself in on Tuesday.
Patel was also charged with homicide by vehicle, involuntary manslaughter, tampering with evidence, careless driving, reckless driving and prohibited text-based communications, according to a report sent by Pennsylvania State Police. Patel was driving on Interstate 95 at around 3:20 am ET when the crash occurred. She was traveling at about 71 miles per hour in her 2022 Ford Mustang Mach-E with the BlueCruise hands-free driving feature and Adaptive Cruise Control systems activated at the time of the crash.




The men, identified as Aktilek Baktybekov and Tolobek Esenbekov, had pulled over to the left side of the highway and exited their vehicles. Patel rear-ended one of the cars and killed both of the men.
In a statement, the Pennsylvania State Police urged drivers to always stay alert and limit distractions when driving. 
“No partially automated vehicle technology should ever be left alone to perform the driving tasks that are required to safely navigate the roads of the Commonwealth,” according to the statement sent to TechCrunch. “While the advancements in technology are immense, always strive to maintain proper control of your vehicle. If you are driving hands free, be aware and ready to regain control if the situation warrants your immediate reaction.”
The fatal crash in Pennsylvania — along with another one that happened in Texas in February — is currently under investigation by the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration’s Office of Defects Investigation. It’s one of a number of ongoing efforts to scrutinize the use of partial automation. But it’s one of the first cases where charges have been brought against the driver, who is supposed to supervise the driver assistance system’s performance and take over if it is about to crash.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[X is hiring staff for security and safety after two years of layoffs]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/x-is-hiring-staff-for-security-and-safety-after-two-years-of-layoffs/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/x-is-hiring-staff-for-security-and-safety-after-two-years-of-layoffs/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T11:35:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nearly two years after the layoffs across X’s trust, safety, and security teams, Elon Musk’s social media company is now trying to hire new employees to help moderate content and secure its platform, according to X’s official job listings. 
In the last month, X posted two dozen job openings evenly split across its safety and cybersecurity teams. 




The jobs on X’s safety team range from director of strategic response on X’s safety team to government affairs managers. On its cybersecurity teams, X is hiring several security engineers and a threat intelligence specialist. 
These are small numbers compared to the number of staff Musk laid off following his $44 billion acquisition of the company, formerly known as Twitter, in late 2022. In April 2023, Musk told the BBC that Twitter, as it wa…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Week in AI: VCs (and devs) are enthusiastic about AI coding tools]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/this-week-in-ai-vcs-and-devs-are-enthusiastic-about-ai-coding-tools/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/this-week-in-ai-vcs-and-devs-are-enthusiastic-about-ai-coding-tools/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T09:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hiya, folks, welcome to TechCrunch’s regular AI newsletter. If you want this in your inbox every Wednesday, sign up here.
This week in AI, two startups developing tools to generate and suggest code — Magic and Codeium — raised nearly half a billion dollars combined. The rounds were high even by AI sector standards, especially considering that Magic hasn’t launched a product or generated revenue yet.




So why the investor enthusiasm? Well, coding isn’t an easy — or inexpensive — business. And there’s demand from both companies and individual developers for ways to streamline the more arduous processes around it.
According to one survey, the average dev spends close to 20% of their workweek maintaining existing code rather than writing anything new. In a separate study, companies said that…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Cosmos Institute, whose founding fellows include Anthropic co-founder Jack Clark, launches grant programs and an AI lab]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/the-cosmos-institute-whose-founding-fellows-include-anthropic-co-founder-jack-clark-launches-grant-programs-and-an-ai-lab/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/the-cosmos-institute-whose-founding-fellows-include-anthropic-co-founder-jack-clark-launches-grant-programs-and-an-ai-lab/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T09:03:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Cosmos Institute, a nonprofit whose founding fellows include Anthropic co-founder Jack Clark and former Defense Department technologist Brendan McCord, has announced a venture program and research initiatives to — in the organization’s words — “cultivate a new generation of technologists and entrepreneurs equipped with deep philosophical thinking to navigate the uncharted territory of our AI age.”
In a blog post, McCord, Cosmos’ chair, said that the Institute will found an AI lab at the University of Oxford called the Human-Centered AI Lab, or “HAI Lab” for short. It’ll be led by Oxford philosopher Philipp Koralus — another of the Institute’s founding fellows — and aim to “translate the philosophical principles of human flourishing into open source software and AI systems.”




What do…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[YouTube debuts new parental controls aimed at teens]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/youtube-debuts-new-parental-controls-aimed-at-teens/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/youtube-debuts-new-parental-controls-aimed-at-teens/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T08:58:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[YouTube is expanding its existing set of parental controls with a new feature that would allow a parent to link their account to their teen’s account in order to gain insight into the teen’s activity across the video-sharing platform, the company announced on Wednesday. Once linked, parents will be alerted to their teen’s channel activity, including the number of uploads, subscriptions, and comments — not the content. They’ll also receive email notifications about events, like a new upload or livestream.
The company tells TechCrunch that the act of linking the account won’t influence the YouTube algorithm in terms of what’s shown to the teen, however, as that’s already personalized to the user. Parents also aren’t able to inform YouTube of the child’s real age via the act of account linkin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[As remote working keeps rolling, Oyster raises $59M Series D at $1.2B valuation]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/as-remote-working-keeps-rolling-oyster-raises-59m-series-d-at-1-2b-valuation/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/as-remote-working-keeps-rolling-oyster-raises-59m-series-d-at-1-2b-valuation/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T08:49:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No one is putting the remote working genie back in the bottle. Which is good news for Oyster, a payroll and HR platform that specializes in distributed workforces – or “global employment” as its marketing paints it. The 2019-founded U.S. startup has just closed a $59 million Series D funding round led by Silver Lake Waterman. 
The new funding, which brings its total raised to date to $286 million, sees its valuation increase slightly – up to $1.2 billion vs the $1B it was valued at back in 2022 (when it raised its $150M Series C). This means Oyster has maintained its market value at a time when many other tech companies have been forced into down-rounds – bucking a painful trend. 




Winding the clock back to 2021 – when the world was in the throws of the pandemic and remote working surge…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tinder update targets college students as dating apps struggle]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/tinder-u-gets-new-features-aimed-at-enhancing-online-dating-for-college-students/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/tinder-u-gets-new-features-aimed-at-enhancing-online-dating-for-college-students/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For the college students who are satisfied with dating apps, which may not be many, Tinder announced Wednesday a series of updates to Tinder U, its in-app feature that caters to current college students ages 18 to 24. This includes new badges to add to their profiles, such as graduation year, major, clubs, and Greek life. Other smaller updates include more simplified enrollment for students and an exclusive Tinder U app icon for iOS users. 
Tinder is also offering U.S. students 50% off any Tinder premium subscription — Plus, Gold, or Platinum — in hopes of gaining more paid users to the platform after losing 400,000 paid users this past quarter. 




Additionally, it’s that time of year when Tinder hosts its annual “Swipe Off” challenge, where the college or university with the most swipe …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ireland’s privacy watchdog ends legal fight with X over data use for AI after it agrees to permanent limits]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/irelands-privacy-watchdog-ends-legal-fight-with-x-over-data-use-for-ai-after-it-agrees-to-permanent-limits/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/irelands-privacy-watchdog-ends-legal-fight-with-x-over-data-use-for-ai-after-it-agrees-to-permanent-limits/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T07:58:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The lead privacy watchdog for X (formerly Twitter) in the European Union has ended court proceedings against the social media platform for processing user data for AI model training without people’s consent. This comes after it said the company had agreed to permanently abide by an undertaking made last month in front of an Irish High Court judge.
X agreed to suspend its processing of European users’ data for AI model training in early August after Ireland’s Data Protection Commission (DPC) initiated legal action against the Elon Musk-owned company in relation to consentless use of people’s information to train its AI chatbot, Grok. 




Meta has faced similar regulatory pushback in the EU over the same data protection issue and announced its own “pause” in this type of processing back in …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[X doubles down on video with a new TV app]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/x-doubles-down-on-video-with-a-new-tv-app/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/x-doubles-down-on-video-with-a-new-tv-app/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T07:29:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Years ago, Twitter tried but eventually walked away from building TV apps after getting a lukewarm reception. Now, as it looks to revive its advertising business, its new incarnation X is hoping for a rerun. The company announced a new TV app available “on several app stores” as part of a wider effort to court more advertisers, creators, and partners around a “video-first platform.” 
That pivot into video will also include a new video tab on X itself, it added. The tab has yet to launch. 




Users are noting that a beta of the TV app is already appearing on Amazon Fire TV and Google TV; we’ve been able to confirm we can see the Amazon Fire TV app ourselves. No sign of the app yet on Apple TV, Roku or other TV platforms.
Twitter’s CEO Linda Yaccarino announced plans for the TV apps initial…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple event 2024: How to watch the iPhone 16 launch]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/apple-event-2024-how-to-watch-the-iphone-16-launch/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/apple-event-2024-how-to-watch-the-iphone-16-launch/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T07:28:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It might have been a brat summer, but Apple thinks it’s “glowtime” for its iPhone 16 event. The company announced that it will host the event to unveil new devices on September 9 at 10 a.m. PT.
The event will take place at the Steve Jobs Theater on Apple’s campus. But for people who won’t be present in person, they can tune in here or watch the stream on Apple’s website.




We expect to see new iPhone 16 and 16 Pro models, as well as updates to the Apple Watch, AirPods and perhaps even new Macs, although those are a big “maybe.”  
Apple unveiled its AI suite, Apple Intelligence, at WWDC 2024 and has rolled out some features to the 15 Pro models through developer betas. These features will make their way to consumers with the public release of iOS 18. Plus, Apple might offer some Apple Intelligence-powered features exclusively for the iPhone 16 lineup.
As always, TechCrunch will be covering the event, bringing you news as it happens.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watch this robotic wheelchair’s compliant wheels take on bumps, rocks and stairs]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/watch-this-robot-wheelchairs-compliant-wheels-take-on-bumps-rocks-and-stairs/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/watch-this-robot-wheelchairs-compliant-wheels-take-on-bumps-rocks-and-stairs/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T07:07:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Korea’s Institute of Machinery and Materials this week showcased a robotic wheelchair with large, deformable wheels that can manage rocks, stairs and other obstacles. During normal operation, the wheel maintains a standard rigid circular form. When it encounters an obstacle, however, it becomes compliant, conforming to the object’s height and shape.
The system, which also appeared in Science Robotics, is surrounded by a “smart chain” structure attached to spokes that alter tension when the chain encounters variations in terrain. The team says the project was inspired by the surface tension properties of water droplets. No word on when — or if — such a system might be commercialized.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mayfield allocates $100M to AI incubator modeled after its entrepreneur-in-residence program]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/mayfield-allocates-100m-to-ai-incubator-modeled-after-its-entrepreneur-in-residence-program/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/mayfield-allocates-100m-to-ai-incubator-modeled-after-its-entrepreneur-in-residence-program/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Navin Chaddha, the leader and managing partner of 55-year-old VC firm Mayfield Fund, has a penchant for approaching venture investing in a way that deviates slightly from other established firms.
When Mayfield raised a $955 million fund last year, Chaddha told TechCrunch the firm didn’t need a multibillion-dollar fund because “copying somebody else is strategy for disaster, strategy for failure.”




The firm is again trying to do something that it sees as unique. On Wednesday, Mayfield said it is launching AI Garage, a $100 million initiative for ideation-stage founders interested in building “AI teammate” companies.
AI Garage wants to distinguish itself from accelerators such as YC or pre-seed programs like Sequoia’s Arc or Greylock’s Edge by modeling the effort on its entrepreneur-in-re…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ilya Sutskever’s startup, Safe Superintelligence, raises $1B]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/ilya-sutskevers-startup-safe-super-intelligence-raises-1b/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/ilya-sutskevers-startup-safe-super-intelligence-raises-1b/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T05:54:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Safe Superintelligence (SSI), the AI startup co-founded by former OpenAI chief scientist Ilya Sutskever, has raised over $1 billion in capital from investors including NFDG (an investment partnership run by Nat Friedman and SSI CEO Daniel Gross), a16z, Sequoia, DST Global and SV Angel.
SSI told Reuters that it plans to use the tranche to acquire computing power and hire researchers and engineers split between Palo Alto and Tel Aviv. As to what exactly they’ll research, SSI isn’t saying quite yet.
Reuters, citing a source familiar, says that the new funding values SSI at $5 billion. 
Prior to SSI, Sutskever headed the now-dismantled Superalignment team at OpenAI, which focused on general AI safety research. Sutskever quietly departed OpenAI months after a highly-publicized fallout between him, several former OpenAI board members and OpenAI CEO Sam Altman over what Sutskever has referred to as a “breakdown in communications.”]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DubClub wants amateur sports betters to win more]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/dubclub-wants-amateur-sports-betters-to-win-more/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/dubclub-wants-amateur-sports-betters-to-win-more/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The American sports betting market produced $10.9 billion in revenue in 2023 for casinos, sportsbooks and iGaming, according to the American Gambling Association. One of the reasons this industry is so lucrative is because the majority of people who bet on sports lose. A three-year-old San Francisco-based startup called DubClub is trying to change that.
“When betting on sports, you are at a structural disadvantage versus the sportsbooks,” DubClub co-founder and CEO Ryan Gaertner, told TechCrunch. “They have more data than the average person. Those companies make money when people lose.”




DubClub hopes to help amateur betters win more by finding experts that may help them better understand which bets to make. DubClub is a platform where amateur sports betters can subscribe to professiona…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dutch clean energy investor SET Ventures lands new €200 million fund, which will go toward digital tech]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/dutch-clean-energy-investor-set-ventures-lands-new-e200-million-fund-which-will-go-toward-digital-tech/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/dutch-clean-energy-investor-set-ventures-lands-new-e200-million-fund-which-will-go-toward-digital-tech/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New climate tech VC firms have emerged in recent years, but existing ones are also raising larger funds. Founded in 2007, Dutch firm SET Ventures is one of the latter. Its fourth fund, which just closed at €200 million, is twice the size of its previous one, and will be deployed into 20 to 25 European startups making renewable energy more mainstream.
SET’s name, pronounced “set,” stands for Sustainable Energy Technologies. Its long track record of investing in European climate-focused startups and article 9 status, which requires a commitment to sustainability as a goal, helped it attract more capital than ever from a mix of corporate and institutional LPs. But managing partner Anton Arts is aware that a larger fund can drive early-stage firms toward writing larger checks at later stages, …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Revefi seeks to automate companies’ data operations]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/revefi-seeks-to-automate-companies-data-operations/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/revefi-seeks-to-automate-companies-data-operations/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sanjay Agrawal and Shashank Gupta, who helped co-found the business intelligence company ThoughtSpot, say that several years ago, they observed that organizations were struggling to deal with the increasing amount of data under their purview.
Even enterprises with robust data analytics and orchestration tools seemed to be having a rough go of it, Agrawal and Gupta say. Maybe so. According to a Deloitte study, 67% of managers aren’t comfortable accessing insights from data analytics platforms, partly due to tech-related challenges.




“Everyone wants to be strategic, but current approaches keep companies trapped in firefighting mode, grappling with routine, preventable operational and tactical tasks,” Agrawal told TechCrunch. “Companies need a modern approach to address their expanding rol…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You.com ‘refocuses’ from AI search to deeper productivity agents with new $50M round]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/you-com-refocuses-from-ai-search-to-deeper-productivity-agents-with-new-50m-round/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/you-com-refocuses-from-ai-search-to-deeper-productivity-agents-with-new-50m-round/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T04:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you build an AI search product, you compete with Google. 
But Google has a lot easier time answering queries with a single, simple answer, such as “how many is a dozen?” than it does answering complex questions like “what influence did Thomas Paine’s ‘Common Sense’ have on Enlightenment ideals?” 




That’s why You.com is betting the company on answering the second type of question.
Emboldened by a new $50 million funding round, the consistently innovative yet often overlooked AI company aims to excel where other AI companies raising billions falter.
As founder and CEO Richard Socher puts it: “Just from first principles, where can you be 10x better than Google?”
It would be futile to compete on the simple questions that make up the vast bulk of Google searches – basic facts, conversions…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bliki: Cycle Time]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/bliki/CycleTime.html</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/bliki/CycleTime.html"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cycle Time is a measure of how long it takes to get a new feature in a
  software system from idea to running in production. In Agile circles, we try
  to minimize cycle time. We do this by defining and implementing very small
  features and minimizing delays in the development process. Although the rough
  notion of cycle time, and the importance of reducing it, is common, there is a
  lot of variations on how cycle time is measured.


A key characteristic of agile software development is a shift from a
  Waterfall Process, where work is decomposed based on
  activity (analysis, coding, testing) to an Iterative Process where work is
  based on a subset of functionality (simple pricing, bulk discount,
  valued-customer discount). Doing this generates a feedback loop where we can learn
  fr…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[reMarkable’s Paper Pro adds color, light and more but keeps the focus on ‘focus’]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/remarkables-paper-pro-adds-color-light-and-more-but-keeps-the-focus-on-focus/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/remarkables-paper-pro-adds-color-light-and-more-but-keeps-the-focus-on-focus/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T03:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The new Paper Pro tablet from reMarkable moves the company’s vision of combining PC with paper closer to reality, adding color and capability while keeping the philosophy of focus intact.
The Norwegian company has been something of an unlikely success story. In a day and age where more and more functionality is crammed into our devices, reMarkable’s approach of doing a few things well — and largely in black and white — seems almost self-defeating. But despite swimming upstream, the company has prospered, growing and funding itself without resorting to venture capital, something few startups can say.




With the first reMarkable tablet, the company established the philosophy of focusing on one document at a time, reading and writing on the device as if it were a piece of paper. The reMarka…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK regulator greenlights Microsoft’s Inflection acquihire, but also designates it a merger]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/uk-regulator-greenlights-microsofts-inflection-acquihire-but-also-designates-it-a-merger/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/uk-regulator-greenlights-microsofts-inflection-acquihire-but-also-designates-it-a-merger/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T03:55:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Good news for Microsoft: The U.K.’s antitrust regulator says that the tech titan’s high-profile acquihire of the team behind AI startup Inflection doesn’t cause competition concerns, and thus it won’t be pursuing a full-scale investigation. 
However, the Competition and Markets Authority (CMA) says that the deal — reportedly valued at around $650 million — does fall under its regulatory purview as a “relevant merger situation,” meaning similar deals in the future may still be investigated on competition grounds — even if a full acquisition has not taken place.
The ‘quasi-merger’
Microsoft launched a new consumer AI division back in March, which Inflection co-founders Mustafa Suleyman and Karén Simonyan (respectively, also previously a co-founder and scientist at Google DeepMind) are spearh…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Lyft’s CEO says ‘it would be insane’ not to go all in on bikeshare]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/lyft-is-going-all-in-on-docked-bikeshare/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/lyft-is-going-all-in-on-docked-bikeshare/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T03:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the summer of 2023, Lyft was contemplating the sale of its micromobility business after receiving strong interest from prospective buyers. Today, the ride-hail company is doubling down on its docked scooter and bikeshare operations, positioning itself as the ideal partner for cities looking to enhance their urban transportation networks. 
Since acquiring shared bike and station provider PBSC Urban Solutions two years ago, Lyft has invested in building and deploying better quality e-bikes and docked e-scooters, as well as a new type of docking station that is solar-powered, modular and able to charge both bikes and scooters. 




As CEO David Risher reviewed Lyft’s micromobility assets, he asked himself: “Do we sell the whole thing, or do we operate it?” 
“E-bikes in particular are growi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spotify launches its evolving playlist, daylist, globally]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/spotify-launches-its-evolving-playlist-daylist-globally/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/04/spotify-launches-its-evolving-playlist-daylist-globally/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T02:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spotify is launching daylist globally. It’s a personalized playlist that evolves throughout the day depending on your listening habits. This rollout comes after the company introduced it first to English-speaking markets last year. The playlist will be available to both free and premium users.
The company said it is also adding support for 14 additional languages, including Arabic, Catalan, French (Canada), French (France), German, Indonesian, Italian, Japanese, Korean, Polish, Portuguese (Brazil), Spanish (Spain), Spanish (Mexico), and Turkish.




Spotify introduced daylist in the U.S., Canada, the U.K., Australia, New Zealand and Ireland in September 2023. In March 2024, the feature was made available in 65 more countries, and now the company is launching the feature in all the markets where Spotify is available.
Spotify noted that after the expansion in March, 70% of daylist users come back weekly to access the playlist. However, the company didn’t specify how many users overall have used this feature or how much music discovery it is driving.
Users can access daylist in the Spotify app through the “Made for You” section or on the web through this link. The playlist and its title update throughout the day with some goofy ones like “bedroom pop banger early morning” or “90s rave rainforest late night.” At the time of launch, Spotify said that it uses data of “niche music and microgenres” that you listen to at a particular time of the day to suggest tracks and update the daylist. 
Users can also save a particular playlist they like by tapping on the three dot menu, selecting “Add to playlist” option, and tapping on “New Playlist” to save that exact daylist to their library.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Boot.dev Beat. September 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.boot.dev/news/bootdev-beat-2024-09/</id>
        <link href="https://blog.boot.dev/news/bootdev-beat-2024-09/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The aracnum was soooooo close to defeating the Hound of Zaggoroth in this month’s boss fight.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Boot.dev Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Impact investors FMO and BlueOrchard back Ghana’s digital lender Fido in $30M Series B round]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/ghanas-digital-lender-fido-30m-series-b-round/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/ghanas-digital-lender-fido-30m-series-b-round/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T19:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital lending platforms have become an easy and swift alternative source of credit for microenterprises and individuals overlooked by traditional banking institutions. These platforms have turned into a lifeline for millions of underbanked and demand will keep growing, pushing the value of the digital lending platform market in the Middle East and Africa to reach $2 billion in the next five years, recording a four-fold growth since 2021.
This is the market opportunity Ghanaian fintech Fido plans to tap as it explores new markets in East and Southern Africa, sustained by fresh $30 million Series B debt-equity funding. The new capital includes a $20 million equity injection from global impact investment manager BlueOrchard and Dutch entrepreneurial development bank FMO.




Initially launc…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PharmEasy still 92% below its peak $5.6 billion valuation, investor estimates]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/pharmeasy-still-92-below-its-peak-5-6-billion-valuation-investor-estimates/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/pharmeasy-still-92-below-its-peak-5-6-billion-valuation-investor-estimates/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T19:38:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Indian online pharmacy startup PharmEasy, once valued at $5.6 billion, is still about 92% below its peak valuation, according to estimates by its investor Janus Henderson. 
According to the British-American global asset firm, which disclosed how it values its shares in the Indian startup in a securities filing, PharmEasy’s implied valuation at the end of June was about $458 million. 




That’s surprising because in April the startup said it had launched a rights issue to raise about $417 million. The rights issue, which allows existing investors to buy new shares in the firm at a much lower valuation, was oversubscribed, PharmEasy co-founder Dharmil Sheth said in a LinkedIn post. 
A regulatory filing showed at the time that the startup had secured about $216 million. Some investors had st…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From their experiences at Uber and PayPal, Palm founders want to make moving cash easier for big companies]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/from-their-experiences-at-uber-and-paypal-palm-founders-want-to-make-moving-cash-easier-for-big-companies/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/from-their-experiences-at-uber-and-paypal-palm-founders-want-to-make-moving-cash-easier-for-big-companies/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Uber, Gurjit Pannu remembers moving billions in cash across bank accounts globally, realizing almost immediately the importance of effective cash flow management. 
Christian Sobkowski, meanwhile, recalls his days working in financial services, most notably at PayPal, where helped expand the company’s business across Europe.




It’s no wonder then, that the two decided to come together as co-CEOs, pairing their financial backgrounds to create a company that, in hindsight, would have made Pannu’s former day job much easier.
“With Treasury teams deciding how the largest corporations move cash around the world, it became obvious that guiding those money flows was worthy of bringing the best talent to re-think how it’s done,” Sobkowski told TechCrunch. 
The result is Palm, launched in 2023 …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Canva has increased prices for its Teams product]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/canva-has-increased-prices-for-its-teams-product/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/canva-has-increased-prices-for-its-teams-product/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T16:45:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Canva, the design platform, is increasing prices steeply for some customers. And it’s blaming the move in part on generative AI.
In the U.S., some Canva Teams subscribers on older pricing plans are seeing the sticker price for a five-person plan jump from $119.99 per year to $500 per year (with a 40% discount for the first 12 months). In Australia, meanwhile, the flat $39.99 AUS (about $26) per-month fee for up to five users has been raised to $13.50 AUS for each user. 




On an individual user basis, Canva Teams prices are now $100 per person, or $10 a month per person, with a minimum of three people required for a Teams plan. Those prices were quietly changed earlier this year for new customers, but now the company is changing the price for customers who’d previously paid a lower price.…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Engineering of Landfills]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41436642</id>
        <link href="https://practical.engineering/blog/2024/9/3/the-hidden-engineering-of-landfills"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T16:40:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://practical.engineering/blog/2024/9/3/the-hidden-engineering-of-landfills
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41436642
Points: 500
# Comments: 305]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>impish9208</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple Event 2024: iPhone 16, Apple Intelligence and all the other expected ‘Glowtime’ reveals]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/apple-event-2024-iphone-16-apple-intelligence-and-all-the-other-expected-glowtime-reveals/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/apple-event-2024-iphone-16-apple-intelligence-and-all-the-other-expected-glowtime-reveals/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T15:26:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes a headline is enough. Apple will reveal the iPhone 16 at its September 9 “It’s Glowtime” event; this much we can tell you for certain. But Apple doesn’t invite us to fly across the country for a single product — not to mention booking a hotel room on the 49ers opening day. Football aside, the timing of the annual event is important, as it’s one last major opportunity to announce a bunch of hardware ahead of the holidays.
The livestream kicks off on Monday at 10 a.m. PT. The invites dropped last week with the “Glowtime” tag line and a color scheme to match. Apple loves to sprinkle small hints into these graphics, and this one appears more on the nose than most.





Apple Intelligence and Siri
Back at WWDC in June, Apple finally revealed its approach to generative AI. The offering…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Snap CEO says the company is testing a ‘simplified’ Snapchat]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/snap-ceo-says-the-company-is-testing-a-simplified-snapchat/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/snap-ceo-says-the-company-is-testing-a-simplified-snapchat/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T15:18:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Snap is testing a “simplified version of Snapchat,” CEO Evan Spiegel wrote in a letter to employees published on Snap’s website Tuesday. The CEO says the simplified version aims to improve the platform’s accessibility and usability. For those that remember Snapchat’s 2018 redesign, this news may do little to stoke confidence.
Spiegel attempted to rally employee spirits with his letter on Tuesday after a depressing year for the company’s stock price, which has fallen nearly 50% in 2024. 




“Investors are concerned that we aren’t growing faster,” said Spiegel in the letter.
The “simplified” Snapchat may be an attempt to capture older users, who are historically perplexed by the app’s not-so-intuitive design. Snapchat does a lot better at attracting younger audiences, who seem to just get t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Neko Health, the body-scanning AI health startup from Spotify’s Daniel Ek, opens in London]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/neko-health-the-body-scanning-ai-health-startup-from-spotifys-daniel-ek-opens-in-london/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/neko-health-the-body-scanning-ai-health-startup-from-spotifys-daniel-ek-opens-in-london/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Prevention is better than cure, as the saying goes. Today, a splashy startup that has taken that concept to heart — literally and figuratively — is expanding.
Neko Health was co-founded by Spotify’s Daniel Ek and Hjalmar Nilsonne with a mission to improve preventative healthcare with annual full body scans and AI-powered insights that can detect conditions like heart disease and skin cancer. Now, the Swedish company is launching in London, its first city outside of its home market. 




For £299 and an hour of your time, the company runs a series of scans and tests that it says creates “millions” of datapoints that help determine your state of health across a range of cardiovascular, metabolic, and other conditions. An in-person meeting with a doctor to discuss the data is included in the …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bitcoin ATMs are a hotbed for scams, FTC says]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/bitcoin-atms-are-a-hotbed-for-scams-ftc-says/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/bitcoin-atms-are-a-hotbed-for-scams-ftc-says/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T13:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Federal Trade Commission (FTC) published a report about increasing fraud at Bitcoin ATMs. These ATMs allow people to turn their cash into crypto, but they’ve become a tool for scammers to perpetrate fraud. Since 2020, the FTC says, fraud at Bitcoin ATMs has ballooned nearly tenfold, and just in the first half of 2024, consumers have lost more than $66 million to these scams.
Scammers use tactics like fake phone calls, messages and security alerts to convince people that they’re in danger, and that they should deposit cash into a Bitcoin ATM to protect it. Then, the scammer may share a QR code to scan at the Bitcoin ATM, which deposits the cash into the scammer’s wallet.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EUCLEAK Side-Channel Attack on the YubiKey 5 Series]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41434500</id>
        <link href="https://ninjalab.io/eucleak/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T12:54:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://ninjalab.io/eucleak/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41434500
Points: 508
# Comments: 187]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GTP</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Volkswagen is rolling out its ChatGPT assistant to the US]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/volkswagen-is-rolling-out-its-chatgpt-assistant-to-the-us/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/volkswagen-is-rolling-out-its-chatgpt-assistant-to-the-us/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T11:44:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Volkswagen is taking its ChatGPT voice assistant experiment on the road. Or more, specifically to vehicles it sells in the United States. 
The German automaker announced in January at CES 2024 plans to add an AI-powered chatbot into all Volkswagen models equipped with its IDA voice assistant. But the U.S. was excluded in that initial rollout.




Now, the automaker is making its ChatGPT-integrated Plus Speech voice assistant — which is an AI chatbot based on Cerence’s Chat Pro product and a large language model from OpenAI — available in new U.S. vehicles. The rollout begins September 6 with the 2025 
2025 Jetta and Jetta GLI models, along with 2024 ID.4 vehicles equipped with an 82-kWh battery. Most 2025 models will offer Plus Speech with AI as they enter the market.
Caveat: A subscription required, although the ID.4 and ID Buzz comes with three years of free access.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn startup best practices with MongoDB, Venture Backed, InterSystems and others at Disrupt 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/learn-startup-best-practices-with-mongodb-venture-backed-intersystems-and-others-at-disrupt-2024/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/learn-startup-best-practices-with-mongodb-venture-backed-intersystems-and-others-at-disrupt-2024/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T10:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From idea to IPO, Disrupt charts startups at every stage on the roadmap to their next breakthrough. TechCrunch will gather some of the startup world’s leading companies — but our partners provide more than just financial support. Their presence at Disrupt gives new and prospective founders the tools, knowledge and community they need to build a successful startup.
Take a look at the latest group of companies ready to help you move your company to the next level. Here’s what they’re doing and where you’ll find them. 




Keep your eye out for our 2024 Breakout sessions, now featuring Venture Backed, providing granular-level visibility and insight, so founders can develop winning strategies for every single investment. Venture Backed will also be hosting their own reception (date and time TB…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Android’s latest update improves text-to-speech, Circle to Search, earthquake alerts and more]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/android-15-release-new-updates/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/android-15-release-new-updates/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Android introduced five updates on Tuesday as part of its latest release of the mobile operating system. Available for smartphones, tablets, and Wear OS watches, the new features include audio descriptions of images, text-to-speech technology for web pages in Chrome, and the ability to look up songs with “Circle to Search,” among other things. 
Initially announced in May, all Android users are officially getting “TalkBack,” an accessibility feature for people who are blind or have low vision. The feature is Google’s version of a screen reader, which provides detailed audio descriptions of digital images. TalkBack is powered by Gemini Nano, Google’s large-language-model-based platform. Users can now hear descriptions of all sorts of images, like online products, photos in their camera roll,…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Android 15 will be available on supported Pixel devices in the coming weeks]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/android-15-will-be-available-on-supported-pixel-devices-in-the-coming-weeks/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/android-15-will-be-available-on-supported-pixel-devices-in-the-coming-weeks/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google announced on Tuesday it’s releasing Android 15 and making its source code available ahead of the coming consumer launch, which will bring the new mobile operating system to supported Pixel devices in the coming weeks. The company also revealed that Android 15 will launch on select devices from Samsung, Honor, iQOO, Lenovo, Motorola, Nothing, OnePlus, Oppo, realme, Sharp, Sony, Tecno, vivo, and Xiaomi in the coming months.
The Android update will bring new additions like Private Space, a feature that lets users silo a portion of the operating system for sensitive information. The software update will also allow users to save their favorite split-screen app combinations for quick access and pin the taskbar permanently on the screen. Other additions include partial screen recording and…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bluesky continues to soar, adding 2M more new users in a matter of days]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/bluesky-continues-to-soar-adding-2m-more-new-users-in-a-matter-of-days/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/bluesky-continues-to-soar-adding-2m-more-new-users-in-a-matter-of-days/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T09:30:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Social networking startup Bluesky continues to benefit from X’s shutdown in Brazil having now added over 2 million new users over the past four days, up from just half a million as of Friday. This rapid growth led some users to encounter the occasional error that would state there were “Not Enough Resources” to handle requests, as Bluesky engineers scrambled to keep the servers stable under the influx of new sign-ups.
As new users downloaded the app, Bluesky jumped to becoming the app to No. 1 in Brazil over the weekend, ahead of Meta’s X competitor, Instagram Threads. According to app intelligence firm Appfigures, Bluesky’s total downloads soared by 10,584% this weekend compared to last, and its downloads in Brazil were up by a whopping 1,018,952%. The growth seems to be having a halo eff…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How India became 5th largest Economy? What lead to the Economic boom?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gfm93K-K3WI</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gfm93K-K3WI"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T09:29:51.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Think School</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The flat-rate real estate startup that’s got big players worried and BNPL’s turning a corner]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/the-flat-rate-real-estate-startup-thats-got-big-players-worried-and-bnpls-turning-a-corner/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/the-flat-rate-real-estate-startup-thats-got-big-players-worried-and-bnpls-turning-a-corner/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T09:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to TechCrunch Fintech! This week, we’re looking at a new real estate startup that’s making big waves with its offering, Klarna and Affirm’s financials, a neobank focused on immigrants that’s growing fast, and more!
To get a roundup of TechCrunch’s biggest and most important fintech stories delivered to your inbox every Tuesday at 8:00 a.m. PT, subscribe here.
The big story


Flat-fee real estate
There’s a whole lot of fintech in the real estate world. And last week, I got the scoop on a new startup called Landian that emerged from stealth to take advantage of recent rule changes related to real estate commissions. In fact, one of its co-founders is also one of the people who successfully sued the National Association of Realtors (NAR) to help facilitate those changes. Buyers have t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[As more Instagram users engage with Stories, the app adds a comments feature]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/instagram-stories-public-comments-feature/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/instagram-stories-public-comments-feature/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T08:39:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Instagram’s latest feature aims to boost user interaction within Stories. The social media platform now allows followers to comment on each other’s Stories, making the experience more community-focused, akin to livestreaming where users can engage in larger discussions.
A few users have already spotted the feature, including marketing strategist Taylor Loren (@taylor.loren on Threads). Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg also posted a screenshot in the company’s Channel. (See below). 




Instagram notes that users will be able to disable the option to have comments posted on their Stories, if they prefer. 


The new feature seems to have been inspired by user behavior. Instagram head, Adam Mosseri, has previously expressed how the Stories format is one of the app’s most popular features and is more widely used than posting content to the main feed. Private messaging is also highly favored by many users who prefer engaging in closed groups with their friends.
The addition of public comments to Stories is part of Instagram’s ongoing efforts to increase engagement on the platform. Most recently, the company added the ability to add music to profiles. There’s also a new feature called “Reveal” that allows users to hide Stories so that followers can only see them after sending a DM.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dragonfly Capital, Galaxy Ventures and NFX share insights on crypto scaling and strategy at TechCrunch Disrupt 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/dragonfly-capital-galaxy-ventures-and-nfx-share-insights-on-crypto-scaling-and-strategy-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2024/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/dragonfly-capital-galaxy-ventures-and-nfx-share-insights-on-crypto-scaling-and-strategy-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2024/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T07:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Curious about how top venture capitalists are positioning themselves for the next wave in the crypto market? 
Dragonfly Capital’s Haseeb Qureshi, Galaxy Ventures’ Will Nuelle, and NFX’s Morgan Beller will share their perspectives on the Fintech Stage at TechCrunch Disrupt 2024. Get a rare glimpse into the evolving strategies, general consensus and anticipated trends of leading investors in the cryptocurrency space. These three experts — combined having backed some of the most significant protocols, exchanges and decentralized applications — are uniquely positioned to discuss the future of blockchain and crypto. 
Expect a deep dive into the latest trends, including institutional involvement, the rise of gaming and metaverse platforms, and the subsequent shift in broader economics. Discover …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing the final agenda for the Builders Stage at TechCrunch Disrupt 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/announcing-the-final-agenda-for-the-builders-stage-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2024/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/announcing-the-final-agenda-for-the-builders-stage-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2024/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Get ready for TechCrunch Disrupt 2024, our signature event for startups of all stages, happening at Moscone West in San Francisco from October 28-30. This year, we’re expecting a massive turnout of 10,000 leaders from the startup and VC community.
As part of the program, we’re thrilled to unveil the complete agenda for the Builders Stage. It’s the culmination of months of hard work and just one of six stages featured at this year’s event, with many more announcements on the horizon.
About the Builders Stage
The Builders Stage serves as a hub for dozens of panels and interviews dedicated to the essential elements of building and financing tech startups. This year, we’re doubling down on our commitment to providing top-tier programming featuring innovation across all stages of a team’s journ…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spotter launches AI tools to help YouTubers brainstorm video ideas, thumbnails and more]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/spotter-launches-ai-tools-youtubers-brainstorm-video-ideas-thumbnails/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/spotter-launches-ai-tools-youtubers-brainstorm-video-ideas-thumbnails/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spotter, the startup that provides financial solutions to content creators, announced Tuesday the launch of its new AI-powered creative suite. Dubbed Spotter Studio, the solution aims to support YouTubers throughout the creative process, such as helping them brainstorm video concepts, generate thumbnail and title ideas, plan projects, organize tasks, and collaborate with their team.
Most notably, it has a feature that analyzes billions of publicly available YouTube videos in order to draw inspiration from similar creators. 




Spotter Studio competes with various AI tools designed for creators, including TubeBuddy and VidIQ, as well as YouTube’s AI-powered inspiration tool, which suggests topics based on data about what viewers are currently watching. However, Spotter Studio claims to dif…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Former Citi, Battery VC has new $378M fund that helps startups land Prudential, Mutual of Omaha, others as investors and customers]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/former-citi-battery-vc-has-new-378m-fund-that-helps-startups-land-prudential/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/former-citi-battery-vc-has-new-378m-fund-that-helps-startups-land-prudential/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PruVen Capital, a fintech and insurance tech venture fund founded by former Benchmark and Citi ventures VC Ramneek Gupta, has closed a new $378.5 million Fund II to invest in financial services and enterprise-focused startups.
This second fund is significant because Gupta expanded it beyond a corporate fund with one main LP – Prudential Financial – into one supported by a number of financial and insurance LPs. Prudential Financial is the lead investor but the fund also includes TIAA, Lincoln Financial, Generali, Nippon Life, Mutual of Omaha and Willis Towers Watson. Prudential was the solo LP in Pruven’s first fund of $300 million.




Gupta expects to wrap up investments from Fund I and begin investing out of Fund II later this month. 
PruVen competes by offering portfolio companies acces…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Halliburton confirms data was stolen in ongoing cyberattack]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/halliburton-confirms-data-was-stolen-in-ongoing-cyberattack/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/halliburton-confirms-data-was-stolen-in-ongoing-cyberattack/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T04:46:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Energy giant Halliburton has confirmed its systems were hacked and that intruders “accessed and exfiltrated information” following a cyberattack last week.
In a brief filing with government regulators on Tuesday, Halliburton said it was “evaluating the nature and scope of the [stolen] information,” and what data breach notifications it is required to make.




Halliburton last week said it took some of its systems offline following the detection of the cyberattack. The company now says it is “working to identify effects of the incident” on its ongoing oil and fracking operations.
When contacted on Tuesday, Halliburton spokesperson Amina Rivera did not comment or say if the company knows what kinds of data were stolen. “We are not commenting beyond what was included in our filing,” said Riv…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elon Musk’s Brazil battle wages on]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/elon-musks-brazil-battle-wages-on/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/elon-musks-brazil-battle-wages-on/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T04:11:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Is Elon’s rumble in the Amazonian jungle on course for a technical knockout? Over the weekend, the Brazilian high court voted to uphold a ban on X that another judge issued the week before for failing to comply with take-down requests. The court will issue fines of up to $9,000 to those who use VPNs to get around that ban. But the debate and drama have not ended there. Mike Masnick over at TechDirt weighs up how the case highlights the complexities of supporting free speech and complying with so-called “hostage laws,” but also how Musk himself, owner of “ExTwitter,” has played different sides depending on what suits him best. Meanwhile, Musk says his satellite communications company Starlink and his other companies have had their assets frozen, as well.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oxylus Energy strikes “beautiful balance” to make e-fuels for aviation and shipping]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/oxylus-energy-strikes-beautiful-balance-to-make-e-fuels-for-aviation-and-shipping/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/oxylus-energy-strikes-beautiful-balance-to-make-e-fuels-for-aviation-and-shipping/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T03:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many airlines and shipping companies say they’ll hit net zero carbon emissions by 2050, but right now they have no clear path toward hitting that target. 
From a scientific perspective, ridding those industries of fossil fuels is possible; economically, it’s not. Or at least not yet, claims a young startup. Oxylus Energy thinks it has the key to one part of the equation.  




The company was spun out of a Yale chemistry lab last year, and it has been working to refine the production of so-called green methanol. Today, most methanol is derived from fossil fuels and used to make petrochemicals, though it can also be used as a transportation fuel. Because of that flexibility, green methanol, which is made without fossil fuels, could rid carbon pollution from a range of industries.
“We think …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Greppability is an underrated code metric]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41430772</id>
        <link href="https://morizbuesing.com/blog/greppability-code-metric/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T02:47:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://morizbuesing.com/blog/greppability-code-metric/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41430772
Points: 564
# Comments: 317]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>thunderbong</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Xavier Niel replaces Coatue’s Laffont on board of TikTok parent ByteDance]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/xavier-niel-replaces-coatues-laffont-on-board-of-tiktok-parent-bytedance/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/xavier-niel-replaces-coatues-laffont-on-board-of-tiktok-parent-bytedance/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T02:34:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[French billionaire Xavier Niel is joining the board of directors of TikTok’s parent, ByteDance, the company told the South China Morning Post. It’s an interesting move as Niel isn’t a name that comes up very often for high-profile board positions.
He is replacing Philippe Laffont, the founder of the New York-based investment firm Coatue Management, on ByteDance’s board, per the report. Coatue has been considering selling a portion of its stake in ByteDance, according to a report by The Information on August 23. 
Niel is the owner of French telecom company Iliad. He has also been an active startup investor with his seed investment firm Kima Ventures and through other investment vehicles. Additionally, he created Station F, a startup campus based in Paris, as well as setting up a computer science school called 42.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clearview AI hit with its largest GDPR fine yet as Dutch regulator considers holding execs personally liable]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/clearview-ai-hit-with-its-largest-gdpr-fine-yet-as-dutch-regulator-considers-holding-execs-personally-liable/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/clearview-ai-hit-with-its-largest-gdpr-fine-yet-as-dutch-regulator-considers-holding-execs-personally-liable/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T02:02:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Clearview AI, the controversial U.S.-based, facial recognition startup that built a searchable database of 30 million images populated by scraping the internet for people’s selfies without their consent, has been hit with its largest privacy fine yet in Europe.
The Netherlands’ data protection authority, Autoriteit Persoonsgegevens (AP), said on Tuesday that it has imposed a penalty of €30.5 million — around $33.7M at current exchange rates — on Clearview AI for a raft of breaches of the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) after confirming the database contains images of Dutch citizens.




This fine is larger than separate GDPR sanctions imposed by data protection authorities in France, Italy, Greece and the U.K. back in 2022.
In a press release, the AP warned it ha…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[X lets you edit DMs — here is how to use the feature]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/x-lets-you-edit-dms-here-is-how-to-use-the-feature/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/03/x-lets-you-edit-dms-here-is-how-to-use-the-feature/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T01:20:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[X, the social network owned by Elon Musk, is finally rolling out one of the most sought-after features for direct messages: the ability to edit the message.
Over the weekend, X made the edit message feature available to iOS users. One of the engineers at the company posted about the roll-out and said the edit messages function will be available on more platforms soon.


save yourself from your own bad decisions (or typos) (or both)
DM edits are here. you’re welcome https://t.co/RzELFRZgfY
— X (@X) August 31, 2024


Here is how you can use it:
Open any direct message chat from your X iOS app.
Long press on any message that you sent or tap on the three-dot menu beside the message.
Select the “Edit message” option to modify the sent message.
According to a support page, there is no time limit for editing the messages. In our testing, we found out that you can also edit older DMs on the platform too. However, you can only make five edits overall to a message. The social network applies the same limit on editing posts as well.




While X said that it keeps a log of edited messages for security reasons, it doesn’t show the version history of edited messages at the moment. 
Users expect to be able to edit their messages in messaging apps, as other chat apps, such as WhatsApp, Telegram, Signal, and Messenger have had this functionality for a while now. Apple also added the ability to edit messages sent via iMessage with iOS 16.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is My Blue Your Blue?]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41430258</id>
        <link href="https://ismy.blue/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T01:17:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://ismy.blue/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41430258
Points: 505
# Comments: 246]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>bpierre</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ziina banks $22M as growth explodes for the UAE-based fintech for small businesses]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/ziina-banks-22m-as-growth-explodes-for-the-uae-based-fintech-for-small-businesses/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/ziina-banks-22m-as-growth-explodes-for-the-uae-based-fintech-for-small-businesses/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T22:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In June 2021, Ziina, fresh from completing YC’s first cohort that year and securing a $7.5 million seed, launched its fintech app to 20,000 retail customers, allowing them to send and receive money. 
Three years later, the Dubai-based startup, which now counts 50,000 retail and business customers after expanding its offerings to meet the needs of micro, small, and medium-sized businesses in the UAE, has netted $22 million in Series A funding led by Altos Ventures.




Indeed, such sizable follow-on funding despite the global funding slowdown underscores investors’ confidence in the fintech company’s growth — the company claims 34% month-over-month growth in customers for the last year, and says its revenues have increased ten-fold over the same period. 
Co-founder and CEO Faisal Toukan tol…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Laptop-leasing startup Fleet wants to become the IT companion for small companies]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/laptop-leasing-startup-fleet-wants-to-become-the-it-companion-for-small-companies/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/laptop-leasing-startup-fleet-wants-to-become-the-it-companion-for-small-companies/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T22:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bootstrapped companies don’t come up in startup news as often as those backed by venture capital, as the former don’t have shiny funding rounds to flaunt. Fleet is a good example of a company that has never raised outside capital but has been growing steadily.
The Paris-based company originally offered a way to rent hardware, so instead of spending a small fortune to acquire a bunch of laptops for their employees, companies could use Fleet to lease devices and pay a monthly fee. The company is now launching several software services on top of its hardware-as-a-service proposition, from device management to cybersecurity and insurance.




As a bootstrapped company, Fleet focused on optimizing its operations to remain as lean as possible and spend less money than it earns. For instance, the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Art of Finishing]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41428705</id>
        <link href="https://www.bytedrum.com/posts/art-of-finishing/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T20:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.bytedrum.com/posts/art-of-finishing/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41428705
Points: 502
# Comments: 120]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>emmorts</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Payroll startup Cercli inks $4M to build the “Rippling for the Middle East and North Africa”]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/cercli-inks-4m-to-build-rippling-for-the-mena-region/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/cercli-inks-4m-to-build-rippling-for-the-mena-region/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T20:04:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While scaling and managing teams at two of the largest unicorns in the Middle East and North Africa (MENA) region, Akeed Azmi and David Reche stumbled on what they believed was a $2 billion opportunity. They realized that their former employers at Careem and Kitopi as well as other local businesses in the region struggled with payroll management and high compliance costs due to human error.
Cercli, the startup they launched in January, addresses this challenge via software it developed that allows businesses in the MENA region to hire, manage and pay their global workforce. The potential of Cercli’s platform has attracted investor interest, leading to $4 million in seed funding led by San Francisco-based Afore Capital, marking the fund’s first deal in the region.




Afore Capital backed C…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Hospital at home’ startup Doccla raises $46 million for its European expansion]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/hospital-at-home-startup-doccla-raises-46-million-for-its-european-expansion/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/hospital-at-home-startup-doccla-raises-46-million-for-its-european-expansion/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hospitals around the world regularly face bed shortages — an issue that can get exacerbated to breaking point when a health scare or other large-scale disaster occurs. A startup called Doccla is bringing technology to bear address the issue: it’s building “virtual bed” tech to help doctors remotely manage patients who have either been discharged early, or in some cases never go to the hospital at all. After gaining traction in the U.K. and Ireland, it’s now raised £35 million ($46 million) to expand in Europe.  
Lakestar is leading the Series B round; Elaia and several existing investors are also participating. The funding comes two years after Doccla raised a $17 million Series A. 




Doccla, which competes with companies like  Graphnet and Huma among others, will use the funding in part…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BigEndian founders hope to use their deep chip experience to help establish India in semiconductors]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/bigendian-embarks-on-surveillance-chip-development-from-india/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/bigendian-embarks-on-surveillance-chip-development-from-india/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[India, despite being home to 20% of the world’s chip designers, lacks a significant presence in the global semiconductor market. However, in recent months, the Indian government has begun investing in an effort to establish the country in semiconductors, as companies worldwide have adopted a “China-plus-one” strategy, seeking alternatives to China. 
BigEndian Semiconductors aims to capitalize on this shift by kicking off development of surveillance chips for cameras. 




Founded in May, the Bengaluru-based fabless design startup is led by CEO Sunil Kumar, a former executive at ARM Broadcom, and Intel, and the rest of the founding team add experience at chipmakers like Broadcom and Cypress Semiconductors. 
Kumar told TechCrunch BigEndian’s founding members had known each other for 25 years…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SparkLabs closes $50M fund to back AI startups]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/sparklabs-closes-50m-fund-to-back-ai-startups/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/sparklabs-closes-50m-fund-to-back-ai-startups/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SparkLabs — an early-stage venture capital firm that has made a name for itself for backing OpenAI as well as a host of other AI startups such as Vectara, Allganize, Kneron, Anthropic, xAI, Glade (YC S23) and Lucidya AI — is gearing up to double down more startups in the space. The VC firm announced Tuesday that it has closed a new $50 million fund, AIM AI Fund, which will back AI startups out of its own AIM-X accelerator in Saudi Arabia as well as other AI startups across the globe.
SparkLabs’ new fund and its wider investment aims underscore the bigger trends that have swirled around artificial intelligence for the last few years. The explosion of interest in generative AI in particular has led to a surge of startups in the space, as well as a rush of investors looking for the next Open …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Did Nehru’s policies fail India?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rPkT8OvjyDU</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rPkT8OvjyDU"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T12:00:12.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Think School</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accel, Docker and Redis will discuss what’s next in open source as a business model at TechCrunch Disrupt 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/accel-docker-and-redis-will-discuss-whats-next-in-open-source-as-a-business-model-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2024/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/accel-docker-and-redis-will-discuss-whats-next-in-open-source-as-a-business-model-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2024/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As companies grapple with the challenge of developing a sustainable business without sacrificing their core principles, open source has evolved from a niche approach to software development into the business model of many successful tech companies. Its principles of transparency and collaboration have fueled innovation, but balancing these ideals with the practical demands of leading a profitable business operation is no easy feat.  
Industry leaders Casey Aylward, partner at Accel; Scott Johnston, CEO of Docker; and Rowan Trollope, CEO of Reddis will be on the SaaS Stage at TechCrunch Disrupt 2024 to explore the complexities of operating using an open source business model and share their views on upcoming shifts in the landscape. 
From navigating funding challenges to balancing open sour…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enhance your brand at TechCrunch Disrupt 2024 by hosting a Side Event]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/enhance-your-brand-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2024-by-hosting-a-side-event/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/enhance-your-brand-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2024-by-hosting-a-side-event/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T07:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whether it’s a sophisticated cocktail party, a casual happy hour, a niche meetup, or a skill-building workshop, “Disrupt Week” offers you the flexibility to host a Side Event that truly represents your brand. 
Take advantage of this opportunity to increase your brand visibility in front of over 10,000 TechCrunch Disrupt 2024 attendees and the vibrant Bay Area tech scene.




Apply for free by September 6. 
Benefits of hosting a Side Event
Amplify your impact: Connect with thousands of Disrupt 2024 attendees and the surrounding tech community. We’ll promote your Side Event across multiple platforms to ensure it reaches our expansive and diverse audience:
Disrupt 2024 Side Event page.
Disrupt 2024 Agenda.
Disrupt 2024 Mobile App Agenda.
Disrupt 2024 attendee emails.
Disrupt 2024 articles.
Discount perks for you and your connections: As a Side Event host, you’ll receive a unique discount code for Disrupt 2024 tickets. Share it with your team and network to ensure everyone benefits from this special offer.
Get started before the deadline
Looking to make a big impact at one of the biggest tech events of the year? Get started on your free application and submit it by September 6 to take advantage of this incredible opportunity.




The application is simple. Submit a short proposal detailing your event’s vision, objectives and logistical requirements. Upon approval, the TechCrunch Disrupt team will collaborate with you to support your event’s success. You’ll be responsible for the planning, execution and associated costs, including registration and communications.
Apply today to make a splash during “Disrupt Week” and enhance your brand’s presence.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A16z’s Joshua Lu says AI is already radically changing video games and Discord is the future]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/a16zs-joshua-lu-says-ai-is-already-radically-changing-video-games-and-discord-is-the-future/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/a16zs-joshua-lu-says-ai-is-already-radically-changing-video-games-and-discord-is-the-future/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Andreessen Horowitz’s partner Joshua Lu knows that, in the video game industry, you can never get too comfortable. When he was head of product at Zynga, he experienced the height of mobile games, working on hits like Words with Friends; then as a vice president at Blizzard Entertainment, he helped produce tentpole hits like Diablo Immortal. And then, as a director of product management at Meta, he learned to see games in new dimensions while working on the VR game, Horizon Worlds. 
“I had to forget what I thought were universal truths and learn a whole new set of ways to do things,” Lu told TechCrunch.




Now Lu wants a front row seat to where video games are heading. After joining the firm as an investor in 2022, Lu helped launch the firm’s Speedrun accelerator, which invests $750,000 ap…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Students and recent grads: 5 days left to save on TechCrunch Disrupt 2024 tickets]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/students-and-recent-grads-5-days-left-to-save-on-techcrunch-disrupt-2024-tickets/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/students-and-recent-grads-5-days-left-to-save-on-techcrunch-disrupt-2024-tickets/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Only 5 days remain to grab a $200 discount on Student Passes for TechCrunch Disrupt 2024. This special offer ends on September 6 at 11:59 p.m. PT. Don’t miss out!
Now that classes are back in session, it’s normal to feel the pressure of rising expenses. Or maybe you’ve recently graduated and are hunting for your first big job. Both scenarios can be hard on your budget.




With over 10,000 tech leaders set to attend Disrupt 2024 from October 28-30 at Moscone West in San Francisco, you have a prime opportunity to make impactful connections and enhance your chances of securing your first post-college job.
Snag your Student Pass at a reduced rate here.
What to expect at Disrupt 2024
Learn from industry leaders
Discover invaluable insights from leaders and visionaries across various sectors, i…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sign or veto: What’s next for California’s AI disaster bill, SB 1047?]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/governor-newsom-must-weigh-the-future-of-californias-ai-industry-with-sb-1047/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/governor-newsom-must-weigh-the-future-of-californias-ai-industry-with-sb-1047/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A controversial California bill to prevent AI disasters, SB 1047, has passed final votes in the state’s Senate and now proceeds to Governor Gavin Newsom’s desk. He must weigh the most extreme theoretical risks of AI systems — including their potential role in human deaths — against potentially thwarting California’s AI boom. He has until September 30 to sign SB 1047 into law, or veto it altogether.
Introduced by state senator Scott Wiener, SB 1047 aims to prevent the possibility of very large AI models creating catastrophic events, such as loss of life or cyberattacks costing more than $500 million in damages.




To be clear, very few AI models exist today that are large enough to be covered by the bill, and AI has never been used for a cyberattack of this scale. But the bill concerns the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CrowdStrike faces onslaught of legal action from faulty software update]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/crowdstrike-faces-onslaught-of-legal-action-from-faulty-software-update/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/crowdstrike-faces-onslaught-of-legal-action-from-faulty-software-update/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When the now infamous CrowdStrike software update took down companies all over the world in July, it was inevitable that lawsuits would follow — and follow they have. Delta suing the company for as much as $500 million in damages and hiring lawyer David Boies is perhaps the highest-profile example.
Among Boies’ wide range of high-profile clients are Theranos, Harvey Weinstein, victims of Jeffrey Epstein, and Al Gore in Bush v. Gore around the results of the 2000 presidential election. He also led the government’s antitrust case against Microsoft in the 1990s.




Even before Delta came forward, shareholders were looking for their pound of flesh, filing a class action lawsuit against CrowdStrike alleging that the company had misled them regarding its software update procedures.
For its part…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Want to branch out beyond Google? Here are some search engines worth checking out]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/want-to-branch-out-beyond-google-here-are-some-search-engines-worth-checking-out/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/want-to-branch-out-beyond-google-here-are-some-search-engines-worth-checking-out/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google has dominated the search space for so long that a U.S. District Court judge recently found that it has acted illegally to maintain a monopoly in online search. You have probably used Google Search for as long as you can remember; it’s what replaced things like phone books and encyclopedias. 
But just because Google runs the most popular engine doesn’t mean you have to use it. If you have never considered a search engine beyond Google, you might be surprised to see what else is out there.




There are many Google Search alternatives on the market that have gained traction. Whether you’re looking for increased privacy, enhanced AI features or just something different, there are some notable options worth checking out.
While Microsoft’s Bing and Yahoo are arguably the most well-known,…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[1M Users]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41422311</id>
        <link href="https://blog.spacehey.com/entry?id=1245177"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T03:13:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://blog.spacehey.com/entry?id=1245177
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41422311
Points: 519
# Comments: 125]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>theneedful</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Customers of Indian crypto exchange WazirX unlikely to recover full funds]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/customers-of-indian-crypto-exchange-wazirx-unlikely-to-recover-full-funds/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/02/customers-of-indian-crypto-exchange-wazirx-unlikely-to-recover-full-funds/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T02:05:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Customers of WazirX, the Indian cryptocurrency exchange that suffered a $234 million hack in July, are unlikely to recover their funds in full through the ongoing restructuring process, a company legal adviser said on Monday.
George Gwee, a director at restructuring firm Kroll working with WazirX, said that at least 43% of the money any customer had in WazirX is unlikely to be recovered. Last week, WazirX asked a Singapore High Court for six months’ protection while it restructures its liabilities.




The best case scenario is a return of “anywhere between 55% and 57% of the funds,” Gwee told journalists. Under a restructuring, WazirX’s priority will be to distribute remaining token assets to users in a pro-rata manner via crypto, it said. The company is holding discussions to share profi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Extreme Pi Boot Optimization]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41420597</id>
        <link href="https://kittenlabs.de/blog/2024/09/01/extreme-pi-boot-optimization/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-01T21:36:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://kittenlabs.de/blog/2024/09/01/extreme-pi-boot-optimization/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41420597
Points: 501
# Comments: 135]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>todsacerdoti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We built the city of Colombo in Cities:Skylines]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41417542</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/team-watchdog/colombo-skylines"/>
        <updated>2024-09-01T15:05:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://github.com/team-watchdog/colombo-skylines
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41417542
Points: 501
# Comments: 178]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>icaruswept</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Validus, a Singapore-based digital SME lending platform, secures $50M debt financing to help enterprises in Indonesia]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/01/validus-a-singapore-based-digital-sme-lending-platform-secures-50m-debt-financing-to-help-enterprises-in-indonesia/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/01/validus-a-singapore-based-digital-sme-lending-platform-secures-50m-debt-financing-to-help-enterprises-in-indonesia/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-01T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Validus, a Singapore-based digital lending platform for small and medium businesses, has secured $50 million in debt financing from HSBC under the ASEAN Growth Fund strategy.
Validus will use the proceeds to support the financial inclusion of micro, small and medium enterprises (MSMEs) in Indonesia, addressing the challenges they face in accessing financial resources.




With 64.2 million MSMEs contributing 61% of Indonesia’s GDP, according to Indonesia’s Ministry for Economic Affairs, the potential for growth is immense. These MSMEs employ about 119.6 million people, which is 97% of the total workforce in the country. However, only about 17.5 million MSME players are tapping into the online ecosystem and e-commerce. Indonesian MSMEs face significant challenges in accessing financing, mai…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple may ditch those old familiar USB-A ports in the new Mac mini]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/01/apple-may-ditch-those-old-familiar-usb-a-ports-in-the-new-mac-mini/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/01/apple-may-ditch-those-old-familiar-usb-a-ports-in-the-new-mac-mini/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-01T12:50:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Mac mini will be the next Apple device to say goodbye to USB-A, according to Bloomberg’s Mark Gurman.
Apple customers have probably gotten used to seeing the familiar, rectangular USB-A ports replaced with their thinner USB-C siblings. And while USB-C has its advantages, the transition can sometimes leave users confused and scrambling for adapters.
The Mac mini, meanwhile, hasn’t been significantly redesigned since 2010, but Gurman says that’s changing this fall. The updated models will include Apple’s new M4 chip, as well as five USB-C ports, plus an Ethernet port, an HDMI connector, and a headphone jack. But the USB-A ports will be gone.
Apple has a “Glowtime” press event scheduled for September 9, where the company is expected to announce the new iPhone 16. The new Mac lineup may not be announced until later in the fall.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The case against AI art]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/01/the-case-against-ai-art/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/01/the-case-against-ai-art/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-01T09:37:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No matter who powerful generative AI becomes, writer Ted Chiang says it will never create true art.
Chiang is one of the most admired science fiction authors writing today, best known for the novella “Story Of Your Life” (which was adapted into the movie “Arrival”). But he’s also published terrific pieces for The New Yorker looking at the dangers and shortcomings of AI.




You should really read his latest article in its entirety, but briefly: Chiang argues that the potential of large language models remains “largely theoretical” — thus far, generative AI has been most successful at “lowering our expectations, both of the things we read and of ourselves when we write anything for others to read. It is a fundamentally dehumanizing technology because it treats us as less than what we are: creators and apprehenders of meaning.”
Even as LLMs improve, Chiang argues that their output will never be art — which he acknowledges is “notoriously hard to define,” but he tries anyway: “Art is something that results from making a lot of choices.” Sure, those choices might not result in a particularly good novel or painting or film, but you’re still “engaged in an act of communication between you and your audience.”
“We are all products of what has come before us, but it’s by living our lives in interaction with others that we bring meaning into the world,” Chiang concludes. “That is something that an auto-complete algorithm can never do, and don’t let anyone tell you otherwise.”]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Palantir’s CTO, and 13th employee, has become a secret weapon for Valley defense tech startups]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/01/tktk/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/01/tktk/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-01T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On August 5, Palantir’s CTO Shyam Sankar stood in front of about 20 nervous new employees at the company’s Washington, D.C. office and gave a speech you’d expect at a new hire meeting: company mission, Palantir’s history, etc. But there was one part that would’ve seemed unfathomable a few years ago: Sankar evangelized the importance of a new wave of defense tech startups, spun up by Palantir, Tesla and SpaceX alums.
The significance was more ideological than financial. Any business Palantir gets from startups is dwarfed by its government contracts, after all. But you can’t put a price on philosophical bedfellows. 




Palantir likes to remind the world that it’s not like other publicly traded companies; i.e. buttoned-up and appropriately distanced from its cowboy private days. Sankar ends …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Founder Mode]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41415023</id>
        <link href="https://paulgraham.com/foundermode.html"/>
        <updated>2024-09-01T07:35:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://paulgraham.com/foundermode.html
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41415023
Points: 744
# Comments: 442]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>bifftastic</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Emotion AI’ may be the next trend for business software, and that could be problematic]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/01/emotion-ai-could-be-the-next-trend-for-business-software-and-that-could-be-problematic/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/01/emotion-ai-could-be-the-next-trend-for-business-software-and-that-could-be-problematic/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-01T07:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As businesses experiment with embedding AI everywhere, one unexpected trend is companies turning to AI to help its many newfound bots better understand human emotion. 
It’s an area called “emotion AI,” according to PitchBook’s new Enterprise Saas Emerging Tech Research report that predicts this tech is on the rise. 




The reasoning goes something like this: If businesses deploy AI assistants to execs and employees, make AI chatbots be front-line salespeople and customer service reps, how can an AI perform well if it doesn’t understand the difference between an angry “What do you mean by that?” and a confused “What do you mean by that?”
Emotion AI claims to be the more sophisticated sibling of sentiment analysis, the pre-AI tech that attempts to distill human emotion from text-based inter…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why do so many home robots still suck?]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/01/why-do-so-many-home-robots-still-suck/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/01/why-do-so-many-home-robots-still-suck/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-01T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“The Jetsons” debuted September 23, 1962. The first episode, titled “Rosey the Robot,” was an origin story of sorts for the titular character, describing how an overworked Jane hired the housekeeper. Sixty-two years after her debut, Rosey remains an important pop cultural touchstone for the unfulfilled promise of home robots.
The home of 2024 isn’t necessarily wholly devoid of robots. According to its own figures, iRobot has sold more than 50 million Roombas. That, meanwhile, is a fraction of the overall number of robot vacuums that have been sold around the globe. Robot lawnmowers and pool cleaners have gained traction as well, though those figures pale in comparison to their vacuuming counterparts.




Home robots’ unfulfilled potential isn’t because of a lack of consumer demand or lack …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From InstaDeep to Paystack: Here are Africa’s biggest startup exits and how much they raised]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/01/from-instadeep-to-paystack-here-are-africas-biggest-startup-exits-and-how-much-they-raised/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/01/from-instadeep-to-paystack-here-are-africas-biggest-startup-exits-and-how-much-they-raised/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-01T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Startups globally have faced challenges over the last couple of years when trying to exit, due to factors like a frozen IPO market and reduced attractiveness to buyers. In addition, large mergers-and-acquisitions (M&A) deals have faced heightened regulatory scrutiny, particularly involving Big Tech or multi-billion-dollar conglomerates.
Notably, a decline in venture investment within any startup ecosystem can often be linked to a lack of exit volume and value. In Africa, for instance, the number of M&A exits peaked at 44 in 2021, when the continent attracted nearly $6 billion in venture capital. However, in 2022, the number of exits dropped to 29, alongside a decrease in venture capital investment to over $3 billion.




Despite these challenges, local investors remain optimistic, saying t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building LLMs from the Ground Up: A 3-Hour Coding Workshop]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41412256</id>
        <link href="https://magazine.sebastianraschka.com/p/building-llms-from-the-ground-up"/>
        <updated>2024-08-31T21:45:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://magazine.sebastianraschka.com/p/building-llms-from-the-ground-up
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41412256
Points: 830
# Comments: 99]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>mdp2021</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Did your car witness a crime?]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41409882</id>
        <link href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/crime/article/tesla-sentry-mode-police-evidence-19731000.php"/>
        <updated>2024-08-31T16:21:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.sfchronicle.com/crime/article/tesla-sentry-mode-police-evidence-19731000.php
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41409882
Points: 271
# Comments: 570]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>danso</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How did Trump win? #businesscasestudy #marketing #election]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xwlnvbagwF0</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xwlnvbagwF0"/>
        <updated>2024-08-31T15:47:20.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Think School</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bolt reportedly threatens legal action against Silverbear Capital]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/08/31/bolt-reportedly-threatens-legal-action-against-silverbear-capital/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/08/31/bolt-reportedly-threatens-legal-action-against-silverbear-capital/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-31T13:56:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the latest twist in Bolt’s aggressive fundraising efforts, the fintech company’s CEO appears to have made a veiled threat of legal action against Silverbear Capital, the investment bank whose involvement in the deal remains in some dispute.
“We believe there was some internal miscommunication at Silverbear Capital, one of our lead investors, which has caused unnecessary confusion,” CEO Justin Grooms wrote in an email reportedly viewed by Forbes. “The fact is, they signed a binding term sheet committing $200 million. Our exceptional legal team at Gibson, Dunn & Crutcher stands ready to represent the company in seeking to enforce our rights vigorously.”




Bolt, which offers tools for one-click e-commerce checkout, did not immediately respond to a request for comment. Silverbear partner …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Buy, Borrow, Die – Explained]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41408772</id>
        <link href="https://old.reddit.com/r/BuyBorrowDieExplained/comments/1f26rsf/buy_borrow_die_explained/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-31T13:35:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://old.reddit.com/r/BuyBorrowDieExplained/comments/1f26rsf/buy_borrow_die_explained/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41408772
Points: 509
# Comments: 420]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nkurz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brazil's X ban is sending lots of people to Bluesky]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41408738</id>
        <link href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/30/24232561/brazil-x-ban-sending-people-bluesky"/>
        <updated>2024-08-31T13:28:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/30/24232561/brazil-x-ban-sending-people-bluesky
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41408738
Points: 391
# Comments: 713]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>rvz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bluesky tops app charts and sees ‘all-time-highs’ after Brazil bans X]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/08/31/bluesky-tops-app-charts-and-sees-all-time-highs-after-brazil-bans-x/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/08/31/bluesky-tops-app-charts-and-sees-all-time-highs-after-brazil-bans-x/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-31T13:10:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Brazilian court’s decision to ban X (formerly Twitter) seems to be benefiting its rivals, especially Bluesky.
The microblogging platform announced late Friday that it was seeing “all-time-highs for activity” with 500,000 new users joining in the previous two days. It’s also number one on the free iPhone app chart in Brazil today, ranking just ahead of Meta’s Threads at number two.




Noting the rankings, Bluesky CEO Jay Graber wrote, “good job Brazil, you made the right choice.”
That growth is particularly impressive for a platform that only fully opened to the public in February and winkingly acknowledged its small size (especially compared to rivals X and Threads) by describing itself as “the short king of social apps.” The company says it had more than 6 million users as of May 2024.
Bluesky was first announced in 2019 as a Twitter-backed initiative to build an open, decentralized social protocol. It has since become an independent public benefit corporation, with Twitter founder Jack Dorsey leaving the board earlier this year.
Elon Musk’s X, meanwhile, has been engaged in an escalating legal fight with Brazil’s Supreme Court Justice Alexandre de Moraes over the company’s refusal to block certain accounts as part of a broader crackdown on what Moraes said is election disinformation. 
X said earlier this month that it would shut down operations in Brazil, with Moraes then warning the company that it would be banned if it did not name a legal representative in the country. He followed through on Friday, and also threatened fines against users who try to circumvent the ban by using a VPN.
As the ban approached, Brazil’s President Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva seemingly bid farewell to his X followers by linking to his other social media accounts — starting with Bluesky.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is OpenAI worth $100B?]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/08/31/is-openai-worth-100b/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/08/31/is-openai-worth-100b/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-31T09:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenAI could reportedly increase its valuation to $100 billion. Nvidia and Apple are apparently in talks to contribute to the company’s next fundraising round, and Thrive Capital would lead the deal should it happen, according to The New York Times. OpenAI’s annualized revenue reportedly eclipsed $3.4 billion early this year, but it’s said to be on track to lose $5 billion by year end as it expands its AI training and staffing efforts.
X is marking some links to NPR’s website as “unsafe.” When users click through to read the latest story about an altercation between a Trump campaign staffer and an Arlington National Cemetery employee, they are met with a warning typically applied to malicious links. It’s unclear why NPR’s site would have triggered this warning, though it raises questions a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon hires the founders of AI robotics startup Covariant]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/08/31/amazon-hires-the-founders-of-robotics-ai-startup-covariant/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/08/31/amazon-hires-the-founders-of-robotics-ai-startup-covariant/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-31T08:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon announced Friday evening that it has hired Covariant’s founders — Pieter Abbeel, Peter Chen, and Rocky Duan — along with “about a quarter” of the startup’s employees. It’s also signed a non-exclusive license to use Covariant’s robotic foundation models.
Earlier this year, Chen told TechCrunch that Covariant is building “a large language model, but for robot language.” In other words, it’s creating AI models for robots, with an initial focus on robotic arms performing common warehouse tasks like bin picking.




“With some of the smartest minds, we will advance fundamental research, marrying our rich expertise to unlock new ways for AI and robots to assist our operations employees,” said Joseph Quinlivan, Vice President of Amazon Fulfillment Technologies & Robotics, in a statement. “[Embedding] Covariant’s AI technology into our existing robot fleet will make them more performant and create real world value for our customers.”
The deal sounds similar to Amazon’s hiring of the founders of AI startup Adept back in June — another deal that gave Amazon access to new talent and technology without having to fully acquire an existing startup.
At the time, The Verge described this approach as a “reverse acquihire,” where tech giants facing antitrust scrutiny can use hiring and licensing deals to disguise their acquisitions, rather than the other way around. 
Covariant, meanwhile, said it will continue operating under the leadership of Ted Stinson and Tianhao Zhang, with Stinson — who’d been the startup’s COO — now stepping into the CEO role. The company added that it remains “dedicated to delivering the Covariant Brain into production environments across a broad set of global industries, including apparel, health and beauty, grocery, and pharmaceuticals.”]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grammy CEO says music industry also has AI concerns]]></title>
        <id>https://techcrunch.com/2024/08/31/grammy-ceo-says-music-industry-also-has-ai-concerns/</id>
        <link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/08/31/grammy-ceo-says-music-industry-also-has-ai-concerns/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-31T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Harvey Mason Jr., CEO of the Recording Academy, caused a stir a few months ago. 
He announced that the organization’s prestigious Grammy Awards would finally accept music made with artificial intelligence. At first, people were confused, and then Mason came out to clarify that he meant only humans can submit to the awards, but that AI can be used in the creative process. 




“It’s a bit of a fine line, but that’s going to evolve,” he told TechCrunch about how the Academy is assessing the use of artificial intelligence in music. “My hope is that we can continue to celebrate human creativity at the highest level.” 
The rise of AI has consumed the arts, just as it has Silicon Valley. Everyone is pondering: Will AI replace me? And within music — what happens to copyright? Royalties? To the ha…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>TechCrunch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is my vision that bad? No, it's just a bug in Apple's Calculator]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41406550</id>
        <link href="https://martin.wojtczyk.de/2024/08/31/is-my-vision-that-bad-no-its-just-a-bug-in-apples-calculator/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-31T04:29:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://martin.wojtczyk.de/2024/08/31/is-my-vision-that-bad-no-its-just-a-bug-in-apples-calculator/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41406550
Points: 604
# Comments: 375]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>wojtczyk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crows are even smarter than we thought]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41405195</id>
        <link href="https://nautil.us/crows-are-even-smarter-than-we-thought-820066/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-30T22:46:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://nautil.us/crows-are-even-smarter-than-we-thought-820066/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41405195
Points: 500
# Comments: 284]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>dnetesn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nike’s Biggest mistake?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FwgcKay6KS4</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FwgcKay6KS4"/>
        <updated>2024-08-30T17:48:11.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Think School</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This speech Made Donald Trump President of USA🇺🇸 : Marketing Strategy Explained]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OeHVlN73aKA</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OeHVlN73aKA"/>
        <updated>2024-08-30T14:30:12.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Think School</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AnandTech Farewell]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41399872</id>
        <link href="https://www.anandtech.com/show/21542/end-of-the-road-an-anandtech-farewell"/>
        <updated>2024-08-30T12:05:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.anandtech.com/show/21542/end-of-the-road-an-anandtech-farewell
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41399872
Points: 2947
# Comments: 587]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>janice1999</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The secret inside One Million Checkboxes]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41395413</id>
        <link href="https://eieio.games/essays/the-secret-in-one-million-checkboxes/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T21:20:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://eieio.games/essays/the-secret-in-one-million-checkboxes/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41395413
Points: 2306
# Comments: 217]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>todsacerdoti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elasticsearch is open source, again]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41394797</id>
        <link href="https://www.elastic.co/blog/elasticsearch-is-open-source-again"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T20:10:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.elastic.co/blog/elasticsearch-is-open-source-again
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41394797
Points: 749
# Comments: 433]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>dakrone</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bypassing airport security via SQL injection]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41392128</id>
        <link href="https://ian.sh/tsa"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T15:53:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://ian.sh/tsa
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41392128
Points: 1959
# Comments: 426]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>iancarroll</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome is entrenching third-party cookies that will mislead users]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41391412</id>
        <link href="https://brave.com/blog/related-website-sets/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T14:53:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://brave.com/blog/related-website-sets/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41391412
Points: 500
# Comments: 307]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>NayamAmarshe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can solar costs keep shrinking?]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41390884</id>
        <link href="https://unchartedterritories.tomaspueyo.com/p/can-solar-costs-keep-shrinking"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T13:57:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://unchartedterritories.tomaspueyo.com/p/can-solar-costs-keep-shrinking
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41390884
Points: 396
# Comments: 602]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GoRudy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Indian Education is a Scam?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LiFA4CBDYDs</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LiFA4CBDYDs"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T13:56:30.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Think School</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Low Cost Mini PCs]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41389931</id>
        <link href="https://lowcostminipcs.com/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T12:03:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While searching for mini PCs for my home server, I figured I'd use the eBay API to find the cheapest ones. Inspired by diskprices.com, I built a static site using Eleventy and a python script that uses regex to parse the data. I tried to include as many filters as possible like OS, Wifi, HDMI etc.
I would like to add power usage, noise levels, PCIe slots but that data is hard to find.
Please let me know if you have any feedback / suggestions.
Thanks!
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41389931
Points: 673
# Comments: 302]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>mjcurl</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenAI is good at unminifying code]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41389185</id>
        <link href="https://glama.ai/blog/2024-08-29-reverse-engineering-minified-code-using-openai"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T10:14:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://glama.ai/blog/2024-08-29-reverse-engineering-minified-code-using-openai
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41389185
Points: 919
# Comments: 301]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>punkpeye</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK rail minister got engineer sacked for raising safety concerns]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41388888</id>
        <link href="https://www.politico.eu/article/uk-rail-minister-peter-hendy-fired-gareth-dennis-engineer-safety-concerns-trains-london-euston-station/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T09:19:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.politico.eu/article/uk-rail-minister-peter-hendy-fired-gareth-dennis-engineer-safety-concerns-trains-london-euston-station/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41388888
Points: 518
# Comments: 289]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>scrlk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Air Con: $1697 for an on/off switch]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41386319</id>
        <link href="https://blog.hopefullyuseful.com/blog/advantage-air-ezone-tablet-diy-repair/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T01:28:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://blog.hopefullyuseful.com/blog/advantage-air-ezone-tablet-diy-repair/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41386319
Points: 1969
# Comments: 476]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ranebo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is this the Reason Why Kolkata Has Failed to Become IT Hub?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QneQbVzfw3E</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QneQbVzfw3E"/>
        <updated>2024-08-28T05:15:39.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Think School</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diffusion models are real-time game engines]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41375548</id>
        <link href="https://gamengen.github.io/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-28T02:59:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://gamengen.github.io
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41375548
Points: 1141
# Comments: 408]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jmorgan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Collection of Free Public APIs That Is Tested Daily]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41371170</id>
        <link href="https://www.freepublicapis.com/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T18:38:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.freepublicapis.com/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41371170
Points: 599
# Comments: 122]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>abhas9</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft donates the Mono Project to the Wine team]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41371106</id>
        <link href="https://www.mono-project.com/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T18:34:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.mono-project.com/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41371106
Points: 1430
# Comments: 478]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>itherseed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Monospace Web]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41370020</id>
        <link href="https://owickstrom.github.io/the-monospace-web/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T17:09:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://owickstrom.github.io/the-monospace-web/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41370020
Points: 608
# Comments: 153]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>mrunseen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Nike Lost $27 billion in one day? : Direct-to- Consumer Business case study]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G_LdttkVQmI</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G_LdttkVQmI"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T13:30:12.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Think School</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zuckerberg claims regret on caving to White House pressure on content]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41365868</id>
        <link href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/08/26/zuckerberg-meta-white-house-pressure-00176399"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T09:50:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.politico.com/news/2024/08/26/zuckerberg-meta-white-house-pressure-00176399
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41365868
Points: 637
# Comments: 1257]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>southernplaces7</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dokku: My favorite personal serverless platform]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41358020</id>
        <link href="https://hamel.dev/blog/posts/dokku/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-26T15:21:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://hamel.dev/blog/posts/dokku/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41358020
Points: 914
# Comments: 270]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>tosh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NSA releases 1982 Grace Hopper lecture]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41356528</id>
        <link href="https://www.nsa.gov/helpful-links/nsa-foia/declassification-transparency-initiatives/historical-releases/view/article/3880193/capt-grace-hopper-on-future-possibilities-data-hardware-software-and-people-1982/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-26T12:37:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.nsa.gov/helpful-links/nsa-foia/declassification-transparency-initiatives/historical-releases/view/article/3880193/capt-grace-hopper-on-future-possibilities-data-hardware-software-and-people-1982/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41356528
Points: 934
# Comments: 222]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>gaws</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fixing a bug in Google Chrome as a first-time contributor]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41355303</id>
        <link href="https://cprimozic.net/blog/fixing-a-bug-in-google-chrome/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-26T09:10:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://cprimozic.net/blog/fixing-a-bug-in-google-chrome/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41355303
Points: 643
# Comments: 165]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ameo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Together let's make sure we create a safer place for women!]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IG36kWLgM6c</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IG36kWLgM6c"/>
        <updated>2024-08-26T07:15:19.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Think School</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Telegram really an encrypted messaging app?]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41350530</id>
        <link href="https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2024/08/25/telegram-is-not-really-an-encrypted-messaging-app/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-25T19:34:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2024/08/25/telegram-is-not-really-an-encrypted-messaging-app/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41350530
Points: 594
# Comments: 581]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>md224</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arrest of Pavel Durov, Telegram CEO, charges of terrorism, fraud, child porn]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41347909</id>
        <link href="https://decripto.org/en/arrest-of-pavel-durov-charges-of-terrorism-fraud-and-child-pornography-he-did-not-cooperate-with-the-authorities-he-risks-20-years-in-prison/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-25T15:20:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://decripto.org/en/arrest-of-pavel-durov-charges-of-terrorism-fraud-and-child-pornography-he-did-not-cooperate-with-the-authorities-he-risks-20-years-in-prison/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41347909
Points: 733
# Comments: 830]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>toss1</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can India become the 3rd largest Economy?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wqxR8Uh3D5o</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wqxR8Uh3D5o"/>
        <updated>2024-08-25T13:54:10.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Think School</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ask HN: What are you working on (August 2024)?]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41342017</id>
        <link href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41342017"/>
        <updated>2024-08-24T22:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What are you working on? Any new ideas that you're thinking about?
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41342017
Points: 634
# Comments: 1416]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>david927</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Telegram founder Pavel Durov arrested at French airport]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41341353</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/article/2024/aug/24/telegram-app-founder-pavel-durov-arrested-at-french-airport"/>
        <updated>2024-08-24T20:46:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.theguardian.com/media/article/2024/aug/24/telegram-app-founder-pavel-durov-arrested-at-french-airport
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41341353
Points: 1175
# Comments: 1038]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>NoxiousPluK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NASA announces Boeing Starliner crew will return on SpaceX Crew-9]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41339667</id>
        <link href="https://twitter.com/NASA/status/1827393397939634503"/>
        <updated>2024-08-24T17:14:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://twitter.com/NASA/status/1827393397939634503
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41339667
Points: 578
# Comments: 730]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ripjaygn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meta cancels high-end mixed reality headset after Apple Vision Pro struggles]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41331369</id>
        <link href="https://www.macrumors.com/2024/08/23/meta-cancels-high-end-headset/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T18:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.macrumors.com/2024/08/23/meta-cancels-high-end-headset/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41331369
Points: 357
# Comments: 526]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>tosh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DOJ sues realpage for algorithmic pricing scheme that harms renters]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41330007</id>
        <link href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-sues-realpage-algorithmic-pricing-scheme-harms-millions-american-renters"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T15:51:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-sues-realpage-algorithmic-pricing-scheme-harms-millions-american-renters
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41330007
Points: 795
# Comments: 624]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>pseudolus</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How will Modi govt fix India’s problems? : ft. Sanjeev Sanyal | Indian Business Podcast EP-13]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3Lgf2WHstBY</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3Lgf2WHstBY"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T15:30:07.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Think School</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Challenging Modi’s Vision for India]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vwDfj70PLW4</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vwDfj70PLW4"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T12:31:52.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Think School</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rewriting Strangler Fig]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/2024-strangler-fig-rewrite.html</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/2024-strangler-fig-rewrite.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T15:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two decades ago, I posted that I found that the strangler fig plant was an interesting metaphor for the gradual replacement of a legacy system. I didn’t refer to the metaphor since, but meanwhile it grew a life of its own. Other people increasingly referred to the strangler fig approach to modernization, and traffic to that post steadily increased: currently it gets about 5000 page views a month, one of the more popular pages on this site. So I decided I needed to update that page, and have rewritten it, focusing on the core activities we need to do to make a success of such a venture.
(This summarizes more detailed writing from Ian Cartwright, Rob Horn, and James Lewis.)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Europeans are getting sick because life is comfortable!]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bwcQCIUxzak</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bwcQCIUxzak"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T14:56:58.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Think School</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to hire great team leaders?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i-DFjuqslgc</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i-DFjuqslgc"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T15:12:51.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Think School</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence is losing hype]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41295923</id>
        <link href="https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2024/08/19/artificial-intelligence-is-losing-hype"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T01:13:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2024/08/19/artificial-intelligence-is-losing-hype
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41295923
Points: 568
# Comments: 782]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>bx376</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Rise and Fall of Old Monk | Business Case Study]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GQPymbqa08A</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GQPymbqa08A"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T14:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Think School</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating Mess With DNS to use PowerDNS]]></title>
        <id>https://jvns.ca/blog/2024/08/19/migrating-mess-with-dns-to-use-powerdns/</id>
        <link href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2024/08/19/migrating-mess-with-dns-to-use-powerdns/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T08:15:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[About 3 years ago, I announced Mess With DNS in
this blog post, a playground
where you can learn how DNS works by messing around and creating records.
I wasn’t very careful with the DNS implementation though (to quote the release blog
post: “following the DNS RFCs? not exactly”), and people started reporting
problems that eventually I decided that I wanted to fix.
the problems
Some of the problems people have reported were:
domain names with underscores weren’t allowed, even though they should be
If there was a CNAME record for a domain name, it allowed you to create other records for that domain name, even if it shouldn’t
you could create 2 different CNAME records for the same domain name, which shouldn’t be allowed
no support for the SVCB or HTTPS record types, which seemed a little comp…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Roblox is the biggest game in the world, but is unprofitable]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41287099</id>
        <link href="https://www.matthewball.co/all/roblox2024"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T01:45:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.matthewball.co/all/roblox2024
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41287099
Points: 466
# Comments: 564]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>mfiguiere</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mpv – A free, open-source, and cross-platform media player]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41277014</id>
        <link href="https://mpv.io/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-17T18:56:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://mpv.io/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41277014
Points: 1113
# Comments: 559]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bluestein</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[X says it is closing operations in Brazil due to judge's content orders]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41275600</id>
        <link href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/x-close-operations-brazil-effective-immediately-2024-08-17/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-17T16:20:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.reuters.com/technology/x-close-operations-brazil-effective-immediately-2024-08-17/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41275600
Points: 344
# Comments: 615]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hexage1814</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is this the end of Adani? Decoding SEBI's response to Hindenburg (Business case study)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tykAc024_8o</id>
        <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tykAc024_8o"/>
        <updated>2024-08-17T15:30:07.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Think School</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Onboarding to a "legacy" codebase with the help of AI]]></title>
        <id>https://martinfowler.com/articles/exploring-gen-ai.html#memo-09</id>
        <link href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/exploring-gen-ai.html#memo-09"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T14:32:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Much of the attention to generative AI in software development is
       about generating code. But it may have a more useful role in helping us
       understand existing code. This is especially true for older codebases
       that are getting hard to maintain (“legacy”) or to improve onboarding in
       teams that have a lot of fluctuation.
Birgitta Böckeler demonstrates the possibilities here
       by picking an issue from an open-source hospital management system and
       exploring how AI could help her deal with it.
more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Fowler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kim Dotcom's extradition to the U.S. given green light by New Zealand]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41254989</id>
        <link href="https://torrentfreak.com/kim-dotcoms-extradition-to-the-u-s-given-green-light-by-new-zealand-240815/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T12:05:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://torrentfreak.com/kim-dotcoms-extradition-to-the-u-s-given-green-light-by-new-zealand-240815/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41254989
Points: 853
# Comments: 1150]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>wut42</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google is a monopoly – the fix isn't obvious]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41254976</id>
        <link href="https://www.theregister.com/2024/08/15/google_monopoly_fix/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T12:02:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://www.theregister.com/2024/08/15/google_monopoly_fix/
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41254976
Points: 266
# Comments: 510]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>rntn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why won't some people pay for news? (2022)]]></title>
        <id>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41249571</id>
        <link href="https://diaspora.glasswings.com/posts/867c94d0ba87013aca41448a5b29e257"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T19:20:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article URL: https://diaspora.glasswings.com/posts/867c94d0ba87013aca41448a5b29e257
Comments URL: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41249571
Points: 168
# Comments: 555]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>dredmorbius</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Speakers for Amsterdam / Netherlands Tech Events]]></title>
        <id>66bc8eef3afb9d0001eea483</id>
        <link href="https://blog.pragmaticengineer.com/speakers-for-amsterdam-netherlands-tech-events/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T11:04:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I (Gergely) sometimes get reachouts to do talks at events in Amsterdam (where I am based,) the Netherlands, or somewhere in Europe. Unfortunately, rarely do talks – I do one conference per year. 
However, I asked around in the community about tech professionals who do paid talks that software engineers]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gergely Orosz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>